<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:ns2="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
  <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3DsubmittedDate%3A%5B202401010000%20TO%20202412312359%5D%26id_list%3D%26start%3D1400%26max_results%3D100" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <ns0:title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=submittedDate:[202401010000 TO 202412312359]&amp;id_list=&amp;start=1400&amp;max_results=100</ns0:title>
  <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/api/VRbRrLu3baSTTByxb+Rs5rcIIxs</ns0:id>
  <ns0:updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</ns0:updated>
  <ns1:totalResults>243692</ns1:totalResults>
  <ns1:startIndex>1400</ns1:startIndex>
  <ns1:itemsPerPage>100</ns1:itemsPerPage>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02092v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T06:40:32Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:40:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>k-Winners-Take-All Ensemble Neural Network</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Ensembling is one approach that improves the performance of a neural network
by combining a number of independent neural networks, usually by either
averaging or summing up their individual outputs. We modify this ensembling
approach by training the sub-networks concurrently instead of independently.
This concurrent training of sub-networks leads them to cooperate with each
other, and we refer to them as "cooperative ensemble". Meanwhile, the
mixture-of-experts approach improves a neural network performance by dividing
up a given dataset to its sub-networks. It then uses a gating network that
assigns a specialization to each of its sub-networks called "experts". We
improve on these aforementioned ways for combining a group of neural networks
by using a k-Winners-Take-All (kWTA) activation function, that acts as the
combination method for the outputs of each sub-network in the ensemble. We
refer to this proposed model as "kWTA ensemble neural networks" (kWTA-ENN).
With the kWTA activation function, the losing neurons of the sub-networks are
inhibited while the winning neurons are retained. This results in sub-networks
having some form of specialization but also sharing knowledge with one another.
We compare our approach with the cooperative ensemble and mixture-of-experts,
where we used a feed-forward neural network with one hidden layer having 100
neurons as the sub-network architecture. Our approach yields a better
performance compared to the baseline models, reaching the following test
accuracies on benchmark datasets: 98.34% on MNIST, 88.06% on Fashion-MNIST,
91.56% on KMNIST, and 95.97% on WDBC.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Abien Fred Agarap</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Arnulfo P. Azcarraga</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1007/978-3-030-92270-2_22</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-92270-2_22" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>Presented in ICONIP 2021</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02092v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02092v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02093v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T06:44:59Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:44:59Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>A new approach to convergence analysis of iterative models with optimal
  error bounds</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this paper, we study a new approach related to the convergence analysis of
Ishikawa-type iterative models to a common fixed point of two non-expansive
mappings in Banach spaces. The main novelty of our contribution lies in the
so-called \emph{optimal error bounds}, which established some necessary and
sufficient conditions for convergence and derived both the error estimates and
bounds on the convergence rates for iterative schemes. Although a special
interest here is devoted to the Ishikawa and modified Ishikawa iterative
sequences, the theory of \emph{optimal error bounds} proposed in this paper can
also be favorably applied to various types of iterative models to approximate
common fixed points of non-expansive mappings.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Minh-Phuong Tran</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thanh-Nhan Nguyen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thai-Hung Nguyen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tan-Phuc Nguyen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tien-Khai Nguyen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cong-Duy-Nguyen Nguyen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Trung-Hieu Huynh</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>29 pages, 9 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02093v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02093v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02094v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-07-15T10:59:38Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:46:19Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>PILoRA: Prototype Guided Incremental LoRA for Federated
  Class-Incremental Learning</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Existing federated learning methods have effectively dealt with decentralized
learning in scenarios involving data privacy and non-IID data. However, in
real-world situations, each client dynamically learns new classes, requiring
the global model to classify all seen classes. To effectively mitigate
catastrophic forgetting and data heterogeneity under low communication costs,
we propose a simple and effective method named PILoRA. On the one hand, we
adopt prototype learning to learn better feature representations and leverage
the heuristic information between prototypes and class features to design a
prototype re-weight module to solve the classifier bias caused by data
heterogeneity without retraining the classifier. On the other hand, we view
incremental learning as the process of learning distinct task vectors and
encoding them within different LoRA parameters. Accordingly, we propose
Incremental LoRA to mitigate catastrophic forgetting. Experimental results on
standard datasets indicate that our method outperforms the state-of-the-art
approaches significantly. More importantly, our method exhibits strong
robustness and superiority in different settings and degrees of data
heterogeneity. The code is available at
\url{https://github.com/Ghy0501/PILoRA}.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haiyang Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fei Zhu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenzhuo Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xu-Yao Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cheng-Lin Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>ECCV 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02094v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02094v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02095v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T06:53:25Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:53:25Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Politics and Propaganda on Social Media: How Twitter and Meta Moderate
  State-Linked Information Operations</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Why do Social Media Corporations (SMCs) engage in state-linked information
operations? Social media can significantly influence the global political
landscape, allowing governments and other political entities to engage in
concerted information operations, shaping or manipulating domestic and foreign
political agendas. In response to state-linked political manipulation tactics
on social media, Twitter and Meta carried out take-down operations against
propaganda networks, accusing them of interfering foreign elections, organizing
disinformation campaigns, manipulating political debates and many other issues.
This research investigates the two SMCs' policy orientation to explain which
factors can affect these two companies' reaction against state-linked
information operations. We find that good governance indicators such as
democracy are significant elements of SMCs' country-focus. This article also
examines whether Meta and Twitter's attention to political regime
characteristics is influenced by international political alignments. This
research illuminates recent trends in SMCs' take-down operations and
illuminating interplay between geopolitics and domestic regime characteristics.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nihat Mugurtay</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Umut Duygu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Onur Varol</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>4 figures, 2 tables and Supp. Info</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02095v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02095v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02096v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T06:54:56Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:54:56Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Isolation and Characterisation of Polypropylene Microplastic-Utilising
  Bacterium from the Antarctic Soil</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Despite its remoteness from other continents, the Antarctic region cannot
escape the aftermath of human activities as it is highly influenced by
anthropogenic impacts that occur both in the regional and global context.
Contamination by microplastics, mostly caused by the improper disposal of
plastic waste, is widely recognised as a serious environmental threat due to
its ubiquity. In recent years, most researchers have focused on microplastic
pollution in the marine ecosystem of Antarctica, while pollution in the
terrestrial environment continues to be neglected. This study was conducted to
investigate the ability of Antarctic soil bacteria to use polypropylene (PP)
microplastics as the sole carbon source. Bushnell Haas (BH) medium inoculated
with bacteria and supplemented PP-microplastics as the sole carbon source was
used in the utilisation test. In this study, the growth response of Dermacoccus
sp. strain AYDL3 was assessed after exposure to PP-microplastics in a basal
medium for 40 days. The weight reduction of the polymer was determined to
further support the growth response. The highest and lowest weight loss
percentages were observed on day 20 (23.0%) and day 10 (7.75%), respectively.
Fourier transforms infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy and scanning electron
microscopy (SEM) analyses were used to confirm the utilisation of
PP-microplastics by strain AYDL3. Results indicate that the soil bacteria
possess a mechanism for breaking down microplastics allowing them to utilise
plastics as energy sources without any pre-treatment. This emphasises the
significance of these soil bacteria to adapt and subsequently manage the
plastic fragments in the soil in the future.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nur Ain Shuhada Ab Razak</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Syahir Habib</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mohd Yunus Abd Shukor</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Siti Aisyah Alias</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jerzy Smykla</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nur Adeela Yasid</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02096v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02096v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02097v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T06:55:49Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T06:55:49Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Preserving Image Properties Through Initializations in Diffusion Models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Retail photography imposes specific requirements on images. For instance,
images may need uniform background colors, consistent model poses, centered
products, and consistent lighting. Minor deviations from these standards impact
a site's aesthetic appeal, making the images unsuitable for use. We show that
Stable Diffusion methods, as currently applied, do not respect these
requirements. The usual practice of training the denoiser with a very noisy
image and starting inference with a sample of pure noise leads to inconsistent
generated images during inference. This inconsistency occurs because it is easy
to tell the difference between samples of the training and inference
distributions. As a result, a network trained with centered retail product
images with uniform backgrounds generates images with erratic backgrounds. The
problem is easily fixed by initializing inference with samples from an
approximation of noisy images. However, in using such an approximation, the
joint distribution of text and noisy image at inference time still slightly
differs from that at training time. This discrepancy is corrected by training
the network with samples from the approximate noisy image distribution.
Extensive experiments on real application data show significant qualitative and
quantitative improvements in performance from adopting these procedures.
Finally, our procedure can interact well with other control-based methods to
further enhance the controllability of diffusion-based methods.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jeffrey Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shao-Yu Chang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kedan Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>David Forsyth</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02097v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02097v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02098v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:08:35Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:08:35Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Stress-testing the coupled behavior of hybrid physics-machine learning
  climate simulations on an unseen, warmer climate</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Accurate and computationally-viable representations of clouds and turbulence
are a long-standing challenge for climate model development. Traditional
parameterizations that crudely but efficiently approximate these processes are
a leading source of uncertainty in long-term projected warming and
precipitation patterns. Machine Learning (ML)-based parameterizations have long
been hailed as a promising alternative with the potential to yield higher
accuracy at a fraction of the cost of more explicit simulations. However, these
ML variants are often unpredictably unstable and inaccurate in \textit{coupled}
testing (i.e. in a downstream hybrid simulation task where they are dynamically
interacting with the large-scale climate model). These issues are exacerbated
in out-of-distribution climates. Certain design decisions such as
``climate-invariant" feature transformation for moisture inputs, input vector
expansion, and temporal history incorporation have been shown to improve
coupled performance, but they may be insufficient for coupled
out-of-distribution generalization. If feature selection and transformations
can inoculate hybrid physics-ML climate models from non-physical,
out-of-distribution extrapolation in a changing climate, there is far greater
potential in extrapolating from observational data. Otherwise, training on
multiple simulated climates becomes an inevitable necessity. While our results
show generalization benefits from these design decisions, the obtained
improvment does not sufficiently preclude the necessity of using multi-climate
simulated training data.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jerry Lin</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mohamed Aziz Bhouri</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tom Beucler</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sungduk Yu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael Pritchard</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>4 Pages, 3 Figures. Accepted to NeurIPS 2023 Climate Change AI
  Workshop. See https://www.climatechange.ai/papers/neurips2023/62</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02098v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02098v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02099v3</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-06-11T02:33:56Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:11:16Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Oceanship: A Large-Scale Dataset for Underwater Audio Target Recognition</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The recognition of underwater audio plays a significant role in identifying a
vessel while it is in motion. Underwater target recognition tasks have a wide
range of applications in areas such as marine environmental protection,
detection of ship radiated noise, underwater noise control, and coastal vessel
dispatch. The traditional UATR task involves training a network to extract
features from audio data and predict the vessel type. The current UATR dataset
exhibits shortcomings in both duration and sample quantity. In this paper, we
propose Oceanship, a large-scale and diverse underwater audio dataset. This
dataset comprises 15 categories, spans a total duration of 121 hours, and
includes comprehensive annotation information such as coordinates, velocity,
vessel types, and timestamps. We compiled the dataset by crawling and
organizing original communication data from the Ocean Communication Network
(ONC) database between 2021 and 2022. While audio retrieval tasks are
well-established in general audio classification, they have not been explored
in the context of underwater audio recognition. Leveraging the Oceanship
dataset, we introduce a baseline model named Oceannet for underwater audio
retrieval. This model achieves a recall at 1 (R@1) accuracy of 67.11% and a
recall at 5 (R@5) accuracy of 99.13% on the Deepship dataset.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zeyu Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Suncheng Xiang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tong Yu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jingsheng Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiacheng Ruan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yanping Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ting Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuzhuo Fu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Accepted by ICIC 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02099v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02099v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02100v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:13:28Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:13:28Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Multiplicative and additive compounds via Kronecker products and
  Kronecker sums</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Compound matrices play an important role in many fields of mathematics and
have recently found new applications in systems and control theory. However,
the explicit formulas for these compounds are non-trivial and not always easy
to use. Here, we derive new formulas for the multiplicative and additive
compounds of a matrix using Kronecker products and sums. This provides a new
approach to matrix compounds based on the well-known and powerful theory of
Kronecker products and sums. We demonstrate several applications of these new
formulas, including deriving a new expression for the additive compound of the
product of two matrices.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ron Ofir</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael Margaliot</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02100v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02100v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.CA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.CA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02101v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:13:34Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:13:34Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>ICI-Free Channel Estimation and Wireless Gesture Recognition Based on
  Cellular Signals</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Device-free wireless sensing attracts enormous attentions since it senses the
environment without additional devices. While cellular signals are good
opportunistic radio sources, the influence of inter-cell interference (ICI) on
wireless sensing has not been adequately addressed. In this letter, we first
investigate the cause of ICI and its impact on wireless sensing. Then we
propose an ICI-free channel estimation method by reconstructing the broadcast
signals of adjacent cells and solving simultaneous equations. Wireless gesture
recognition can be greatly benefited by ICI mitigation. Finally, we build a
prototype system to receive the commercial 4G-LTE signals, and demonstrate the
accuracies of wireless gesture recognition under various conditions.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rui Peng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yafei Tian</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shengqian Han</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02101v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02101v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02102v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:14:06Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:14:06Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Numerical Simulation and Aerodynamic Optimization of Two-Stage Axial
  High-Pressure Turbine Blades</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Gas turbine engines are highly efficient and powerful because of their
high-pressure turbines (HPTs). Furthermore, stationary blades shape and prepare
high-pressure gas for efficient utilization by moving blades. Consequently,
optimizing the geometric features of both stationary and moving blades during
the first and second stages of HPT is necessary. By considering stagger, inlet,
and outlet angles of the first and second stages of blades as design variables
and polytropic efficiency as an objective, this study examines HPT performance.
The performance characteristics of the turbine are examined using Computational
Fluid Dynamics (CFD). To model the objective functions of the design variables,
the Design of Experiments (DOE) method is employed. A Genetic Algorithm (GA)
optimizes torque, power, and polytropic efficiency. Optimization provides
valuable insights into optimal design principles. As shown by the simulation
results, stagger, inlet, and outlet angles affect turbine performance. Through
GA optimization, torque, power, and polytropic efficiency are improved by 8.4%,
0.69%, and 1.2%, respectively. As a result of these improvements, the
optimization approach has been demonstrated to be effective in optimizing
turbine performance. Upon examining the recommended design points, it becomes
clear that stagger, inlet, and outlet angles of blades have a greater impact on
performance than others.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Seyed Ehsan Hosseini</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Saeid Jafaripanah</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zoheir Saboohi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02102v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02102v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.flu-dyn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10269v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:14:42Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:14:42Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Robust Multi-Sensor Multi-Target Tracking Using Possibility Labeled
  Multi-Bernoulli Filter</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  With the increasing complexity of multiple target tracking scenes, a single
sensor may not be able to effectively monitor a large number of targets.
Therefore, it is imperative to extend the single-sensor technique to
Multi-Sensor Multi-Target Tracking (MSMTT) for enhanced functionality. Typical
MSMTT methods presume complete randomness of all uncertain components, and
therefore effective solutions such as the random finite set filter and
covariance intersection method have been derived to conduct the MSMTT task.
However, the presence of epistemic uncertainty, arising from incomplete
information, is often disregarded within the context of MSMTT. This paper
develops an innovative possibility Labeled Multi-Bernoulli (LMB) Filter based
on the labeled Uncertain Finite Set (UFS) theory. The LMB filter inherits the
high robustness of the possibility generalized labeled multi-Bernoulli filter
with simplified computational complexity. The fusion of LMB UFSs is derived and
adapted to develop a robust MSMTT scheme. Simulation results corroborate the
superior performance exhibited by the proposed approach in comparison to
typical probabilistic methods.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Han Cai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chenbao Xue</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jeremie Houssineau</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhirun Xue</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10269v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.10269v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02103v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:16:39Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:16:39Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>When ideals properly extend the class of Arbault sets</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this article we continue the investigation of generalized version of
Arbault sets, that was initiated in \cite{DGT} but look at the picture from the
most general point of view where ideals come into play. While Arbault sets can
be naturally associated with the Frechet ideal $Fin$, in \cite{DGT} it was
observed that when $Fin$ is replaced by the natural density ideal
$\mathcal{I}_d$ one can obtain a strictly larger class of trigonometric thin
sets containing Arbault sets. From the set theoretic point of view a natural
question arises as whether one can broaden the picture and specify a class of
ideals (instead of a single ideal) each of which would have the similar effect.
As a natural candidate, we focus on a special class of ideals, namely,
non-$snt$ ideals ($snt$ stands for ``strongly non translation invariant") which
properly contains the class of translation invariant ideals ($\varsupsetneq
Fin$) and happens to contain ideals generated by simple density functions as
also certain non-negative regular summability matrices (but not all) which can
be seen from \cite{DG6}. We consider the resulting class of
$\mathcal{I}$-Arbault sets and it is observed that for each such ideal, the
class of $\mathcal{I}$-Arbault sets not only properly contains the class of
classical Arbault sets \cite{Ar} but also a large subfamily of
$\mathbf{N}$-sets (also called ``sets of absolute convergence") \cite{Ft} while
being contained in the class of weak Dirichlet sets. %In particular it properly
contains the family of $\mathbf{N}_0$-sets which have been extensively used in
the literature (see \cite{Ar, Ka, Ko}). Though distinct from the class of
$\mathbf{N}$-sets, this happens to be a new class strictly lying between the
class of Arbault sets and the class of weak Dirichlet sets.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pratulananda Das</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ayan Ghosh</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02103v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02103v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02457v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:18:32Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:18:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>eCIL-MU: Embedding based Class Incremental Learning and Machine
  Unlearning</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  New categories may be introduced over time, or existing categories may need
to be reclassified. Class incremental learning (CIL) is employed for the
gradual acquisition of knowledge about new categories while preserving
information about previously learned ones in such dynamic environments. It
might also be necessary to also eliminate the influence of related categories
on the model to adapt to reclassification. We thus introduce class-level
machine unlearning (MU) within CIL. Typically, MU methods tend to be
time-consuming and can potentially harm the model's performance. A continuous
stream of unlearning requests could lead to catastrophic forgetting. To address
these issues, we propose a non-destructive eCIL-MU framework based on embedding
techniques to map data into vectors and then be stored in vector databases. Our
approach exploits the overlap between CIL and MU tasks for acceleration.
Experiments demonstrate the capability of achieving unlearning effectiveness
and orders of magnitude (upto $\sim 278\times$) of acceleration.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiwei Zuo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhuo Tang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bin Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kenli Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Anwitaman Datta</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02457v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02457v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02104v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-06-13T06:15:45Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:22:05Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Single-photon scattering and bound states in a one-dimensional waveguide
  with topological giant atom</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We investigate the single photon scattering and bound states in a coupled
resonator waveguide (CRW) which couples to a topological giant atom (TGA) via
two distant sites. Here, the TGA is constructed by a one dimensional
Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH) chain with finite length. By modulating the
topological phase of the TGA, the incident photon in the CRW can be completely
reflected or transmitted, and is therefore beneficial to design the coherent
photonic device. Meanwhile, we also achieve two pairs of bound states locating
respectively above and blow the continuum. Whether the gap is open or closed
depends on the boundary condition of the TGA. Therefore, the combination of the
topology and the interference provides us an exciting opportunity to manipulate
the photonic state in the context of waveguide quantum electrodynamics.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wei Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tian Tian</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhihai Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>7 Pages, 6 Figures, Comments are welcomed</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02104v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02104v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02105v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:26:52Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:26:52Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Perceptions of Humanoid Robots in Caregiving: A Study of Skilled Nursing
  Home and Long Term Care Administrators</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  As the aging population increases and the shortage of healthcare workers
increases, the need to examine other means for caring for the aging population
increases. One such means is the use of humanoid robots to care for social,
emotional, and physical wellbeing of the people above 65. Understanding skilled
and long term care nursing home administrators' perspectives on humanoid robots
in caregiving is crucial as their insights shape the implementation of robots
and their potential impact on resident well-being and quality of life. This
authors surveyed two hundred and sixty nine nursing homes executives to
understand their perspectives on the use of humanoid robots in their nursing
home facilities. The data was coded and results revealed that the executives
were keen on exploring other avenues for care such as robotics that would
enhance their nursing homes abilities to care for their residents. Qualitative
analysis reveals diverse perspectives on integrating humanoid robots in nursing
homes. While acknowledging benefits like improved engagement and staff support,
concerns persist about costs, impacts on human interaction, and doubts about
robot effectiveness. This highlights complex barriers financial, technical, and
human and emphasizes the need for strategic implementation. It underscores the
importance of thorough training, role clarity, and showcasing technology
benefits to ensure efficiency and satisfaction among staff and residents.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rana Imtiaz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Arshia Khan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>7 pages</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02105v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02105v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02106v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-05T13:05:16Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:28:56Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Cadmium Zinc Telluride (CZT) photon counting detector Characterisation
  for soft tissue imaging</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The use of photon counting detection technology has resulted in significant
X-ray imaging research interest in recent years. Computed Tomography (CT)
scanners can benefit from photon-counting detectors, which are new technology
with the potential to overcome key limitations of conventional CT detectors.
Researchers are still studying the effectiveness and sensitivity of
semiconductor detector materials in photon counting detectors for detecting
soft tissue contrasts. This study aimed to characterize the performance of the
Cadmium Zinc Telluride photon counting detector in identifying various tissues.
An optimal frame rate per second (FPS) of CZT detector was evaluated by setting
the X-ray tube voltage and current at 25 keV, 35 keV and 0.5 mA, 1.0 mA
respectively by keeping the optimum FPS fixed, the detector energy thresholds
were set in small steps from 15 keV to 35 keV and the Currents were set for
X-ray tubes in ranges of 0.1 mA to 1.0 mA to find the relationship between
voltage and current of the X-ray source and counts per second (CPS). The
samples i.e., fat, liver, muscles, paraffin wax, and contrast media were
stacked at six different thickness levels in a stair-step chamber made from
Plexi-glass. X-ray transmission at six different thicknesses of tissue samples
was also examined for five different energy (regions) thresholds (21 keV, 25
keV, 29 keV, 31 keV, and 45 keV) to determine the effect on count per second
(CPS). In this study, 12 frames per second is found to be the optimum frame
rate per second (FPS) based on the spectral response of an X-ray source and CPS
has a linear relationship with X-ray tube current as well. It was also noted
that A sample's thickness also affects its X-ray transmission at different
energy thresholds. A high sensitivity and linearity of the detectors make them
suitable for use in both preclinical and medical applications.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>K. Hameed</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rafidah Zainon</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mahbubunnabi Tamal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>29 pages and 11 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02106v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02106v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.ins-det" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.ins-det" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.med-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02107v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:32:54Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:32:54Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Non-standard neutrino interactions mediated by a light scalar at DUNE</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We investigate the effect on neutrino oscillations generated by
beyond-the-standard-model interactions between neutrinos and matter.
Specifically, we focus on scalar-mediated non-standard interactions (NSI) whose
impact fundamentally differs from that of vector-mediated NSI. Scalar NSI
contribute as corrections to the neutrino mass matrix rather than the matter
potential and thereby predict distinct phenomenology from the vector-mediated
ones. Similar to vector-type NSI, the presence of scalar-mediated neutrino NSI
can influence measurements of oscillation parameters in long-baseline neutrino
oscillation experiments, with a notable impact on CP measurement in the case of
DUNE. Our study focuses on the effect of scalar NSI on neutrino oscillations,
using DUNE as an example. We introduce a model-independent parameterization
procedure that enables the examination of the impact of all non-zero scalar NSI
parameters simultaneously. Subsequently, we convert DUNE's sensitivity to the
NSI parameters into projected sensitivity concerning the parameters of a light
scalar model. We compare these results with existing non-oscillation probes.
Our findings reveal that the region of the light scalar parameter space
sensitive to DUNE is predominantly excluded by non-oscillation probes, except
for scenarios with very light mediator mass.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bhaskar Dutta</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sumit Ghosh</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kevin J. Kelly</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tianjun Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Adrian Thompson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ankur Verma</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>21 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02107v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02107v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02108v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:38:40Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:38:40Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>An eigenvalue problem for self-similar patterns in Hele-Shaw flows</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Hele-Shaw problems are prototypes to study the interface dynamics. Linear
theory suggests the existence of self-similar patterns in a Hele-Shaw flow.
That is, with a specific injection flux the interface shape remains unchanged
while its size increases. In this paper, we explore the existence of
self-similar patterns in the nonlinear regime and develop a rigorous nonlinear
theory characterizing their fundamental features. Using a boundary integral
formulation, we pose the question of self-similarity as a generalized nonlinear
eigenvalue problem, involving two nonlinear integral operators. The flux
constant $C$ is the eigenvalue and the corresponding self-similar pattern
$\mathbf{x}$ is the eigenvector. We develop a quasi-Newton method to solve the
problem and show the existence of nonlinear shapes with $k$-fold dominated
symmetries. The influence of initial guesses on the self-similar patterns is
investigated. We are able to obtain a desired self-similar shape once the
initial guess is properly chosen. Our results go beyond the predictions of
linear theory and establish a bridge between the linear theory and simulations.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wang Xiao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lingyu Feng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kai Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Meng Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02108v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02108v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02109v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:38:54Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:38:54Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Local electronic structure of dilute hydrogen in $β$-MnO$_{2}$</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The electronic and magnetic states of $\beta$-MnO$_{2}$ in terms of hydrogen
impurities have been investigated by muon spin rotation ($\mu$SR) technique
combined with density-functional theory (DFT) calculations for muon as
pseudo-hydrogen. We found that 85% of implanted muons are localized in the
oxygen channels of the rutile structure and behave as interstitial protons
(Mu$^{+})$ except those (7.6%) forming a charge-neutral state (Mu$^{0})$ at 2.3
K, which indicates that interstitial hydrogen acts as a shallow donor within
less than 0.1 meV of ionization energy. The residual 15% of muons are
attributed to those related to lattice imperfection as Mn vacancies. Detailed
analyses combined with DFT approach suggested that the muon is localized at the
center of the oxygen channel due to its large zero-point vibration energy.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>H. Okabe</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>M. Hiraishi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>A. Koda</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>S. Takeshita</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>K. M. Kojima</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>I. Yamauchi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>T. Ohsawa</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>N. Ohashi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>H. Sato</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>R. Kadono</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.103.155121</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.103.155121" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>8 pages, 8 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns2:journal_ref>Phys. Rev. B 103, 155121 (2021)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02109v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02109v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02993v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-05-27T07:04:19Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:39:26Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>ReFusion: Improving Natural Language Understanding with
  Computation-Efficient Retrieval Representation Fusion</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Retrieval-based augmentations (RA) incorporating knowledge from an external
database into language models have greatly succeeded in various
knowledge-intensive (KI) tasks. However, integrating retrievals in
non-knowledge-intensive (NKI) tasks is still challenging. Existing works focus
on concatenating retrievals with inputs to improve model performance.
Unfortunately, the use of retrieval concatenation-based augmentations causes an
increase in the input length, substantially raising the computational demands
of attention mechanisms. This paper proposes a new paradigm of RA named
\textbf{ReFusion}, a computation-efficient Retrieval representation Fusion with
bi-level optimization. Unlike previous works, ReFusion directly fuses the
retrieval representations into the hidden states of models. Specifically,
ReFusion leverages an adaptive retrieval integrator to seek the optimal
combination of the proposed ranking schemes across different model layers.
Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed ReFusion can achieve
superior and robust performance in various NKI tasks.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shangyu Wu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ying Xiong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yufei Cui</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xue Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Buzhou Tang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tei-Wei Kuo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chun Jason Xue</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02993v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02993v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02110v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:43:40Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:43:40Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Significance of Anatomical Constraints in Virtual Try-On</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The system of Virtual Try-ON (VTON) allows a user to try a product virtually.
In general, a VTON system takes a clothing source and a person's image to
predict the try-on output of the person in the given clothing. Although
existing methods perform well for simple poses, in case of bent or crossed arms
posture or when there is a significant difference between the alignment of the
source clothing and the pose of the target person, these methods fail by
generating inaccurate clothing deformations. In the VTON methods that employ
Thin Plate Spline (TPS) based clothing transformations, this mainly occurs for
two reasons - (1)~the second-order smoothness constraint of TPS that restricts
the bending of the object plane. (2)~Overlaps among different clothing parts
(e.g., sleeves and torso) can not be modeled by a single TPS transformation, as
it assumes the clothing as a single planar object; therefore, disregards the
independence of movement of different clothing parts. To this end, we make two
major contributions. Concerning the bending limitations of TPS, we propose a
human AnaTomy-Aware Geometric (ATAG) transformation. Regarding the overlap
issue, we propose a part-based warping approach that divides the clothing into
independently warpable parts to warp them separately and later combine them.
Extensive analysis shows the efficacy of this approach.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Debapriya Roy</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sanchayan Santra</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Diganta Mukherjee</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bhabatosh Chanda</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:2208.08076</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02110v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02110v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02111v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:44:51Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:44:51Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Edge ideals of some edge-weighted graphs</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This paper presents exact formulas for the regularity and depth of powers of
edge ideals of an edge-weighted star graph. Additionally, we provide exact
formulas for the regularity of powers of the edge ideal of an edge-weighted
integrally closed path, as well as lower bounds on the depth of powers of such
an edge ideal.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Guangjun Zhu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shiya Duan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yijun Cui</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiaxin Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02111v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02111v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.AC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="Primary 13F20, 13C15, 05C22, Secondary 05E40" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02112v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:45:38Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:45:38Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Singularity-agnostic incomplete U-statistics for testing polynomial
  constraints in Gaussian covariance matrices</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Testing the goodness-of-fit of a model with its defining functional
constraints in the parameters could date back to Spearman (1927), who analyzed
the famous "tetrad" polynomial in the covariance matrix of the observed
variables in a single-factor model. Despite its long history, the Wald test
typically employed to operationalize this approach could produce very
inaccurate test sizes in many situations, even when the regular conditions for
the classical normal asymptotics are met and a very large sample is available.
  Focusing on testing a polynomial constraint in a Gaussian covariance matrix,
we obtained a new understanding of this baffling phenomenon: When the null
hypothesis is true but "near-singular", the standardized Wald test exhibits
slow weak convergence, owing to the sophisticated dependency structure inherent
to the underlying U-statistic that ultimately drives its limiting distribution;
this can also be rigorously explained by a key ratio of moments encoded in the
Berry-Esseen bound quantifying the normal approximation error involved. As an
alternative, we advocate the use of an incomplete U-statistic to mildly tone
down the dependence thereof and render the speed of convergence agnostic to the
singularity status of the hypothesis. In parallel, we develop a Berry-Esseen
bound that is mathematically descriptive of the singularity-agnostic nature of
our standardized incomplete U-statistic, using some of the finest
exponential-type inequalities in the literature.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dennis Leung</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nils Sturma</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02112v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02112v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.ST" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.TH" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02994v3</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-23T04:43:56Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:45:49Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Blending Is All You Need: Cheaper, Better Alternative to
  Trillion-Parameters LLM</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In conversational AI research, there's a noticeable trend towards developing
models with a larger number of parameters, exemplified by models like ChatGPT.
While these expansive models tend to generate increasingly better chat
responses, they demand significant computational resources and memory. This
study explores a pertinent question: Can a combination of smaller models
collaboratively achieve comparable or enhanced performance relative to a
singular large model? We introduce an approach termed "blending", a
straightforward yet effective method of integrating multiple chat AIs. Our
empirical evidence suggests that when specific smaller models are
synergistically blended, they can potentially outperform or match the
capabilities of much larger counterparts. For instance, integrating just three
models of moderate size (6B/13B paramaeters) can rival or even surpass the
performance metrics of a substantially larger model like ChatGPT (175B+
paramaters). This hypothesis is rigorously tested using A/B testing
methodologies with a large user base on the Chai research platform over a span
of thirty days. The findings underscore the potential of the "blending"
strategy as a viable approach for enhancing chat AI efficacy without a
corresponding surge in computational demands.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaoding Lu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zongyi Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Adian Liusie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Vyas Raina</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Vineet Mudupalli</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuwen Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>William Beauchamp</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02994v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02994v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02113v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:49:32Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:49:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Source-Free Online Domain Adaptive Semantic Segmentation of Satellite
  Images under Image Degradation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Online adaptation to distribution shifts in satellite image segmentation
stands as a crucial yet underexplored problem. In this paper, we address
source-free and online domain adaptation, i.e., test-time adaptation (TTA), for
satellite images, with the focus on mitigating distribution shifts caused by
various forms of image degradation. Towards achieving this goal, we propose a
novel TTA approach involving two effective strategies. First, we progressively
estimate the global Batch Normalization (BN) statistics of the target
distribution with incoming data stream. Leveraging these statistics during
inference has the ability to effectively reduce domain gap. Furthermore, we
enhance prediction quality by refining the predicted masks using global class
centers. Both strategies employ dynamic momentum for fast and stable
convergence. Notably, our method is backpropagation-free and hence fast and
lightweight, making it highly suitable for on-the-fly adaptation to new domain.
Through comprehensive experiments across various domain adaptation scenarios,
we demonstrate the robust performance of our method.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fahim Faisal Niloy</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kishor Kumar Bhaumik</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Simon S. Woo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>ICASSP 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02113v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02113v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02114v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-10-25T01:07:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:49:49Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Chebyshev Subdivision and Reduction Methods for Solving Multivariable
  Systems of Equations</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We present a new algorithm for finding isolated zeros of a system of
real-valued functions in a bounded interval in $\mathbb{R}^n$. It uses the
Chebyshev proxy method combined with a mixture of subdivision, reduction
methods, and elimination checks that leverage special properties of Chebyshev
polynomials. We prove the method has R-quadratic convergence locally near
simple zeros of the system. We also analyze the temporal complexity and the
numerical stability of the algorithm and provide numerical evidence in
dimensions up to three that the method is both fast and accurate on a wide
range of problems. The algorithm should also work well in higher dimensions.
Our tests show that the algorithm outperforms other standard methods on this
problem of finding all real zeros in a bounded domain. Our Python
implementation of the algorithm is publicly available on GitHub.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Erik Parkinson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kate Wall</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jane Slagle</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Daniel Treuhaft</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xander de la Bruere</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Samuel Goldrup</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Timothy Keith</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Peter Call</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tyler J. Jarvis</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02114v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02114v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.AG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="65H10" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02115v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:50:24Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:50:24Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Using LLM to select the right SQL Query from candidates</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Text-to-SQL models can generate a list of candidate SQL queries, and the best
query is often in the candidate list, but not at the top of the list. An
effective re-rank method can select the right SQL query from the candidate list
and improve the model's performance. Previous studies on code generation
automatically generate test cases and use them to re-rank candidate codes.
However, automatic test case generation for text-to-SQL is an understudied
field. We propose an automatic test case generation method that first generates
a database and then uses LLMs to predict the ground truth, which is the
expected execution results of the ground truth SQL query on this database. To
reduce the difficulty for LLMs to predict, we conduct experiments to search for
ways to generate easy databases for LLMs and design easy-to-understand prompts.
Based on our test case generation method, we propose a re-rank method to select
the right SQL query from the candidate list. Given a candidate list, our method
can generate test cases and re-rank the candidate list according to their pass
numbers on these test cases and their generation probabilities. The experiment
results on the validation dataset of Spider show that the performance of some
state-of-the-art models can get a 3.6\% improvement after applying our re-rank
method.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhenwen Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tao Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>8 pages</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02115v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02115v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02116v3</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-03-02T11:09:25Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:52:00Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Starling: An I/O-Efficient Disk-Resident Graph Index Framework for
  High-Dimensional Vector Similarity Search on Data Segment</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  High-dimensional vector similarity search (HVSS) is gaining prominence as a
powerful tool for various data science and AI applications. As vector data
scales up, in-memory indexes pose a significant challenge due to the
substantial increase in main memory requirements. A potential solution involves
leveraging disk-based implementation, which stores and searches vector data on
high-performance devices like NVMe SSDs. However, implementing HVSS for data
segments proves to be intricate in vector databases where a single machine
comprises multiple segments for system scalability. In this context, each
segment operates with limited memory and disk space, necessitating a delicate
balance between accuracy, efficiency, and space cost. Existing disk-based
methods fall short as they do not holistically address all these requirements
simultaneously. In this paper, we present Starling, an I/O-efficient
disk-resident graph index framework that optimizes data layout and search
strategy within the segment. It has two primary components: (1) a data layout
incorporating an in-memory navigation graph and a reordered disk-based graph
with enhanced locality, reducing the search path length and minimizing disk
bandwidth wastage; and (2) a block search strategy designed to minimize costly
disk I/O operations during vector query execution. Through extensive
experiments, we validate the effectiveness, efficiency, and scalability of
Starling. On a data segment with 2GB memory and 10GB disk capacity, Starling
can accommodate up to 33 million vectors in 128 dimensions, offering HVSS with
over 0.9 average precision and top-10 recall rate, and latency under 1
millisecond. The results showcase Starling's superior performance, exhibiting
43.9$\times$ higher throughput with 98% lower query latency compared to
state-of-the-art methods while maintaining the same level of accuracy.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mengzhao Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weizhi Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaomeng Yi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Songlin Wu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhangyang Peng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiangyu Ke</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yunjun Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaoliang Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rentong Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Charles Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1145/3639269</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3639269" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>This paper has been accepted by SIGMOD 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02116v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02116v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.DB" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.DB" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02117v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:55:53Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:55:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Mobile ALOHA: Learning Bimanual Mobile Manipulation with Low-Cost
  Whole-Body Teleoperation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Imitation learning from human demonstrations has shown impressive performance
in robotics. However, most results focus on table-top manipulation, lacking the
mobility and dexterity necessary for generally useful tasks. In this work, we
develop a system for imitating mobile manipulation tasks that are bimanual and
require whole-body control. We first present Mobile ALOHA, a low-cost and
whole-body teleoperation system for data collection. It augments the ALOHA
system with a mobile base, and a whole-body teleoperation interface. Using data
collected with Mobile ALOHA, we then perform supervised behavior cloning and
find that co-training with existing static ALOHA datasets boosts performance on
mobile manipulation tasks. With 50 demonstrations for each task, co-training
can increase success rates by up to 90%, allowing Mobile ALOHA to autonomously
complete complex mobile manipulation tasks such as sauteing and serving a piece
of shrimp, opening a two-door wall cabinet to store heavy cooking pots, calling
and entering an elevator, and lightly rinsing a used pan using a kitchen
faucet. Project website: https://mobile-aloha.github.io
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zipeng Fu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tony Z. Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chelsea Finn</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Project website: https://mobile-aloha.github.io (Zipeng Fu and Tony
  Z. Zhao are project co-leads, Chelsea Finn is the advisor)</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02117v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02117v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02118v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-06-27T11:51:31Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:58:13Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Radio Map-Based Spectrum Sharing for Joint Communication and Sensing</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The sixth-generation (6G) network is expected to provide both communication
and sensing (C&amp;S) services. However, spectrum scarcity poses a major challenge
to the harmonious coexistence of C&amp;S systems. Without effective cooperation,
the interference resulting from spectrum sharing impairs the performance of
both systems. This paper addresses C&amp;S interference within a distributed
network. Different from traditional schemes that require pilot-based
high-frequency interactions between C&amp;S systems, we introduce a third party
named the radio map to provide the large-scale channel state information (CSI).
With large-scale CSI, we optimize the transmit power of C&amp;S systems to maximize
the signal-to-interference-plus-noise ratio (SINR) for the radar detection,
while meeting the ergodic rate requirement of the interfered user. Given the
non-convexity of both the objective and constraint, we employ the techniques of
auxiliary-function-based scaling and fractional programming for simplification.
Subsequently, we propose an iterative algorithm to solve this problem.
Simulation results corroborate our idea that the extrinsic information, i.e.,
positions and surroundings, is effective to decouple C&amp;S interference.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xionran Fang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wei Feng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yunfei Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dingxi Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ning Ge</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiyong Feng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yue Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02118v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02118v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02119v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-14T10:11:21Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:58:47Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Generalized Spectral Form Factor in Random Matrix Theory</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The spectral form factor (SFF) plays a crucial role in revealing the
statistical properties of energy level distributions in complex systems. It is
one of the tools to diagnose quantum chaos and unravel the universal dynamics
therein. The definition of SFF in most literature only encapsulates the
two-level correlation. In this manuscript, we extend the definition of SSF to
include the high-order correlation. Specifically, we introduce the standard
deviation of energy levels to define correlation functions, from which the
generalized spectral form factor (GSFF) can be obtained by Fourier transforms.
GSFF provides a more comprehensive knowledge of the dynamics of chaotic
systems. Using random matrices as examples, we demonstrate new dynamics
features that are encoded in GSFF. Remarkably, the GSFF is complex, and both
the real and imaginary parts exhibit universal dynamics. For instance, in the
two-level correlated case, the real part of GSFF shows a dip-ramp-plateau
structure akin to the conventional counterpart, and the imaginary part for
different system sizes converges in the long time limit. For the two-level
GSFF, the closed analytical forms of the real part are obtained and consistent
with numerical results. The results of the imaginary part are obtained by
numerical calculation. Similar analyses are extended to three-level GSFF.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiyang Wei</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chengming Tan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ren Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>10 pages, 6 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02119v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02119v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02120v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T07:59:32Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T07:59:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Quadratic Discontinuous Galerkin methods for Unilateral Contact Problem</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this article, we employ discontinuous Galerkin (DG) methods for the finite
element approximation of the frictionless unilateral contact problem using
quadratic finite elements over simplicial triangulation. We first establish an
optimal \textit{a priori} error estimates under the appropriate regularity
assumption on the exact solution $\b{u}$. Further, we analyze \textit{a
posteriori} error estimates in the DG norm wherein, the reliability and
efficiency of the proposed \textit{a posteriori} error estimator is addressed.
The suitable construction of discrete Lagrange multiplier $\b{\lambda_h}$ and
some intermediate operators play a key role in developing \textit{a posteriori}
error analysis. Numerical results presented on uniform and adaptive meshes
illustrate and confirm the theoretical findings.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kamana Porwal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tanvi Wadhawan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02120v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02120v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02458v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-10-07T14:20:42Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:00:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Data-Centric Foundation Models in Computational Healthcare: A Survey</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The advent of foundation models (FMs) as an emerging suite of AI techniques
has struck a wave of opportunities in computational healthcare. The interactive
nature of these models, guided by pre-training data and human instructions, has
ignited a data-centric AI paradigm that emphasizes better data
characterization, quality, and scale. In healthcare AI, obtaining and
processing high-quality clinical data records has been a longstanding
challenge, ranging from data quantity, annotation, patient privacy, and ethics.
In this survey, we investigate a wide range of data-centric approaches in the
FM era (from model pre-training to inference) towards improving the healthcare
workflow. We discuss key perspectives in AI security, assessment, and alignment
with human values. Finally, we offer a promising outlook of FM-based analytics
to enhance the performance of patient outcome and clinical workflow in the
evolving landscape of healthcare and medicine. We provide an up-to-date list of
healthcare-related foundation models and datasets at
https://github.com/Yunkun-Zhang/Data-Centric-FM-Healthcare .
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yunkun Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jin Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zheling Tan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lingfeng Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kexin Ding</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mu Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shaoting Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dequan Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Survey content updated to include recent research work and progress</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02458v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02458v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02121v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-07-04T07:17:50Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:07:58Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Characterizing pedestrian contact interaction trajectories to understand
  spreading risk in human crowds</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  A spreading process can be observed when particular information, substances,
or diseases spread through a population over time in social and biological
systems. It is widely believed that contact interactions among individual
entities play an essential role in the spreading process. Although contact
interactions are often influenced by geometrical conditions, little attention
has been paid to understand their effects, especially on contact duration among
pedestrians. To examine how the pedestrian flow setups affect contact duration
distribution, we have analyzed trajectories of pedestrians in contact
interactions collected from pedestrian flow experiments of uni-, bi- and
multi-directional setups. Based on turning angle entropy and efficiency, we
have classified the type of motion observed in the contact interactions. We
have found that the majority of contact interactions in the unidirectional flow
setup can be categorized as confined motion, hinting at the possibility of
long-lived contact duration. However, ballistic motion is more frequently
observed in the other flow conditions, yielding frequent, brief contact
interactions. Our results demonstrate that observing more confined motions is
likely associated with the increase of parallel contact interactions regardless
of pedestrian flow setups. This study highlights that the confined motions tend
to yield longer contact duration, suggesting that the infectious disease
transmission risk would be considerable even for low transmissibility. These
results have important implications for crowd management in the context of
minimizing spreading risk. This work is an extended version of Kwak et al.
(2023) presented at the 2023 International Conference on Computational Science
(ICCS).
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jaeyoung Kwak</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael H. Lees</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wentong Cai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1016/j.jocs.2024.102358</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jocs.2024.102358" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>25 pages, 21 figures, 6 tables</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02121v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02121v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10270v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:11:03Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:11:03Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Migrating Birds Optimization-Based Feature Selection for Text
  Classification</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This research introduces a novel approach, MBO-NB, that leverages Migrating
Birds Optimization (MBO) coupled with Naive Bayes as an internal classifier to
address feature selection challenges in text classification having large number
of features. Focusing on computational efficiency, we preprocess raw data using
the Information Gain algorithm, strategically reducing the feature count from
an average of 62221 to 2089. Our experiments demonstrate MBO-NB's superior
effectiveness in feature reduction compared to other existing techniques,
emphasizing an increased classification accuracy. The successful integration of
Naive Bayes within MBO presents a well-rounded solution. In individual
comparisons with Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO), MBO-NB consistently
outperforms by an average of 6.9% across four setups. This research offers
valuable insights into enhancing feature selection methods, providing a
scalable and effective solution for text classification
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cem Kaya</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zeynep Hilal Kilimci</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mitat Uysal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Murat Kaya</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10270v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.10270v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02122v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-02-07T07:36:34Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:11:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>PEFT for Speech: Unveiling Optimal Placement, Merging Strategies, and
  Ensemble Techniques</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning (PEFT) is increasingly recognized as an
effective method in speech processing. However, the optimal approach and the
placement of PEFT methods remain inconclusive. Our study conducts extensive
experiments to compare different PEFT methods and their layer-wise placement
adapting Differentiable Architecture Search (DARTS). We also explore the use of
ensemble learning to leverage diverse PEFT strategies. The results reveal that
DARTS does not outperform the baseline approach, which involves inserting the
same PEFT method into all layers of a Self-Supervised Learning (SSL) model. In
contrast, an ensemble learning approach, particularly one employing majority
voting, demonstrates superior performance. Our statistical evidence indicates
that different PEFT methods learn in varied ways. This variation might explain
why the synergistic integration of various PEFT methods through ensemble
learning can harness their unique learning capabilities more effectively
compared to individual layer-wise optimization.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tzu-Han Lin</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>How-Shing Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hao-Yung Weng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kuang-Chen Peng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zih-Ching Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hung-yi Lee</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Accepted to ICASSP 2024 Self-supervision in Audio, Speech and Beyond
  (SASB) workshop</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02122v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02122v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10218v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:11:47Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:11:47Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>AntiDeepFake: AI for Deep Fake Speech Recognition</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this research study, we propose a modern artificial intelligence (AI)
approach to recognize deepfake voice, also known as generative AI cloned
synthetic voice. Our proposed AI technology, called AntiDeepFake, consists of
all main pipelines from data to evaluation in the whole picture. We provide
experimental results and scores for all our proposed methods. The main source
code for our approach is available in the provided link:
https://github.com/enkhtogtokh/antideepfake repository.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Enkhtogtokh Togootogtokh</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christian Klasen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:2308.12734 by other authors</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.10218v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2402.10218v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02123v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:13:47Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:13:47Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Simultaneous observations of a breakout current sheet and a flare
  current sheet in a coronal jet event</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Previous studies have revealed that solar coronal jets triggered by the
eruption of mini-filaments (MFs) conform to the famous magnetic-breakout
mechanism. In such scenario, a breakout current sheet (BCS) and a flare current
sheet (FCS) should be observed during the jets. With high spatial and temporal
resolution data from the SDO, the NVST, the RHESSI, the Wind, and the GOES, we
present observational evidence of a BCS and a FCS formation during coronal jets
driven by a MF eruption occurring in the active region NOAA 11726 on 2013 April
21. Magnetic field extrapolation show that the MF was enclosed by a fan-spine
magnetic structure. The MF was activated by flux cancellation under it, and
then slowly rose. A BCS formed when the magnetic fields wrapping the MF
squeezed to antidirectional external open fields. Simultaneously, one thin
bright jet and two bidirectional jet-like structures were observed. As the MF
erupted as a blowout jet, a FCS was formed when the two distended legs inside
the MF field came together. One end of the FCS connected the post-flare loops.
The peak temperature of BCS was calculated to be 2.5 MK. The length, width and
peak temperature of FCS was calculated to be 4.35-4.93 Mm, 1.31-1.45 Mm, and
2.5 MK, respectively. The magnetic reconnection rate associated with the FCS
was estimated to be from 0.266 to 0.333. This event also related to a type III
radio burst, indicating its influence on interplanetary space. These
observations support the scenario of the breakout model as the trigger
mechanism of coronal jets, and flux cancellation was the driver of this event.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Liheng Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaoli Yan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhike Xue</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhe Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Qingmin Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yijun Hou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jincheng Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Huadong Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>14 pages, 10 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02123v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02123v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02459v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:19:21Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:19:21Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Characterization of pedestrian contact interaction trajectories</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  A spreading process can be observed when a particular behavior, substance, or
disease spreads through a population over time in social and biological
systems. It is widely believed that contact interactions among individual
entities play an essential role in the spreading process. Although the contact
interactions are often influenced by geometrical conditions, little attention
has been paid to understand their effects especially on contact duration among
pedestrians. To examine how the pedestrian flow setups affect contact duration
distribution, we have analyzed trajectories of pedestrians in contact
interactions collected from pedestrian flow experiments of uni-, bi- and
multi-directional setups. Based on standardized maximal distance, we have
classified types of motions observed in the contact interactions. We have found
that almost all motion in the unidirectional flow setup can be characterized as
subdiffusive motion, suggesting that the empirically measured contact duration
tends to be longer than one estimated by ballistic motion assumption. However,
Brownian motion is more frequently observed from other flow setups, indicating
that the contact duration estimated by ballistic motion assumption shows good
agreement with the empirically measured one. Furthermore, when the difference
in relative speed distributions between the experimental data and ballistic
motion assumption is larger, more subdiffusive motions are observed. This study
also has practical implications. For instance, it highlights that geometrical
conditions yielding smaller difference in the relative speed distributions are
preferred when diseases can be transmitted through face-to-face interactions.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jaeyoung Kwak</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael H. Lees</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wentong Cai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1007/978-3-031-35995-8_2</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-35995-8_2" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>15 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:2401.02121</ns2:comment>
    <ns2:journal_ref>Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 14073, pp. 18--32 (2023)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02459v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02459v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02124v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:19:27Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:19:27Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>ACP-ESM: A novel framework for classification of anticancer peptides
  using protein-oriented transformer approach</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Anticancer peptides (ACPs) are a class of molecules that have gained
significant attention in the field of cancer research and therapy. ACPs are
short chains of amino acids, the building blocks of proteins, and they possess
the ability to selectively target and kill cancer cells. One of the key
advantages of ACPs is their ability to selectively target cancer cells while
sparing healthy cells to a greater extent. This selectivity is often attributed
to differences in the surface properties of cancer cells compared to normal
cells. That is why ACPs are being investigated as potential candidates for
cancer therapy. ACPs may be used alone or in combination with other treatment
modalities like chemotherapy and radiation therapy. While ACPs hold promise as
a novel approach to cancer treatment, there are challenges to overcome,
including optimizing their stability, improving selectivity, and enhancing
their delivery to cancer cells, continuous increasing in number of peptide
sequences, developing a reliable and precise prediction model. In this work, we
propose an efficient transformer-based framework to identify anticancer
peptides for by performing accurate a reliable and precise prediction model.
For this purpose, four different transformer models, namely ESM, ProtBert,
BioBERT, and SciBERT are employed to detect anticancer peptides from amino acid
sequences. To demonstrate the contribution of the proposed framework, extensive
experiments are carried on widely-used datasets in the literature, two versions
of AntiCp2, cACP-DeepGram, ACP-740. Experiment results show the usage of
proposed model enhances classification accuracy when compared to the
state-of-the-art studies. The proposed framework, ESM, exhibits 96.45 of
accuracy for AntiCp2 dataset, 97.66 of accuracy for cACP-DeepGram dataset, and
88.51 of accuracy for ACP-740 dataset, thence determining new state-of-the-art.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zeynep Hilal Kilimci</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mustafa Yalcin</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02124v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02124v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="q-bio.BM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02125v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:21:18Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:21:18Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Dispersion with Fixed Diagonal Matrices: Exchange energy correction and
  an assessment of the Becke-Roussel exchange hole</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  An exchange-correction to the Fixed Diagonal Matrices (FDM) method is
introduced to improve accuracy when employing a single reference wavefunction.
Also, the performance of the Becke-Roussel exchange-hole for approximating the
pair density mediated integrals is explored. With the exchange-correction, the
FDM procedure yields dispersion coefficients for closed-shell atoms on par with
highly correlated methods when using Hartree-Fock or Kohn-Sham pair density.
Conversely, the Becke-Roussel exchange-hole results in an overestimation of the
dispersion coefficients for closed-shell atoms. In general, the FDM method
fails in underestimating the dispersion coefficients of open-shell atoms and
ions.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Timo Weckman</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>16 pages, 4 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02125v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02125v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02126v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:21:30Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:21:30Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Unified Diffusion-Based Rigid and Non-Rigid Editing with Text and Image
  Guidance</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Existing text-to-image editing methods tend to excel either in rigid or
non-rigid editing but encounter challenges when combining both, resulting in
misaligned outputs with the provided text prompts. In addition, integrating
reference images for control remains challenging. To address these issues, we
present a versatile image editing framework capable of executing both rigid and
non-rigid edits, guided by either textual prompts or reference images. We
leverage a dual-path injection scheme to handle diverse editing scenarios and
introduce an integrated self-attention mechanism for fusion of appearance and
structural information. To mitigate potential visual artifacts, we further
employ latent fusion techniques to adjust intermediate latents. Compared to
previous work, our approach represents a significant advance in achieving
precise and versatile image editing. Comprehensive experiments validate the
efficacy of our method, showcasing competitive or superior results in
text-based editing and appearance transfer tasks, encompassing both rigid and
non-rigid settings.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiacheng Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ping Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wei Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>15 pages, 13 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02126v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02126v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02127v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:25:05Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:25:05Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Measurement-induced bistability in the excited states of a transmon</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  High power measurement-induced cavity response is investigated in the |g&gt;,
|e&gt;, and |f&gt; states of a transmon. All the states exhibit photon blockades
above a certain critical value, a phenomenon that has previously been
understood based on the bistability of semiclassical Duffing oscillators. The
measurement-induced state transition (MIST) to high-level transmon states is
expected to be one contributor to the bistability; however, the critical values
measured in the |e&gt; and |f&gt; states are not coincident with the MIST. To
understand this discrepancy, we utilize the recently developed semiclassical
dynamics model of a cavity photon state. The appearance of dim and bright
cavity states obtained from the model's steady-state solution leads to the
photon blockades at lower critical photon numbers, and this can explain the
response of the bistable region in the |e&gt; and |f&gt; states.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jeakyung Choi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hyeok Hwang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Eunseong Kim</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>19 pages, 5 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02127v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02127v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02128v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:26:20Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:26:20Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Correlated sensing with a solid-state quantum multi-sensor system for
  atomic-scale structural analysis</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Developing superior quantum sensing strategies ranging from ultra-high
precision measurement to complex structural analysis is at the heart of quantum
technologies. While strategies using quantum resources, such as entanglement
among sensors, to enhance the sensing precision have been abundantly
demonstrated, the signal correlation among quantum sensors is rarely exploited.
Here we develop a novel sensing paradigm exploiting the signal correlation
among multiple quantum sensors to resolve overlapping signals from multiple
targets that individual sensors can't resolve and complex structural
construction struggles with. With three nitrogen-vacancy centers as a quantum
electrometer system, we demonstrate this multi-sensor paradigm by resolving
individual defects' fluctuating electric fields from ensemble signals. We image
the three-dimensional distribution of 16 dark electronic point-defects in
diamond with accuracy approaching 1.7 nm via a GPS-like localization method.
Furthermore, we obtain the real-time charge dynamics of individual point
defects and visualize how the dynamics induce the well-known optical spectral
diffusion. The multi-sensor paradigm extends the quantum sensing toolbox and
offers new possibilities for structural analysis.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wentao Ji</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhaoxin Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuhang Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhihao Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jingyang Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Siheng Dai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yu Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pei Yu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mengqi Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kangwei Xia</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fazhan Shi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ya Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiangfeng Du</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02128v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02128v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02129v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-03-27T17:51:56Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:30:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Gravitational Slip parameter and Gravitational Waves in Einstein-Cartan
  theory</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We study the evolution of scalar and tensor cosmological perturbations in the
framework of the Einstein-Cartan theory of gravity. The value of the
gravitational slip parameter which is defined as the ratio of the two scalar
potentials in the Newtonian gauge, can be used to determine whether or not the
gravity is modified. We calculate the value of slip parameter in the
Einstein-Cartan cosmology and show that it falls within the observed range. We
also discuss the evolution of the cosmic gravitational waves as another measure
of the modification of gravity.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Maryam Ranjbar</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Siamak Akhshabi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mohsen Shadmehri</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-024-12670-4</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjc/s10052-024-12670-4" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>12 pages, 15 figures, References added</ns2:comment>
    <ns2:journal_ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 84, 316 (2024)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02129v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02129v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02130v4</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-10-15T04:06:44Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:31:47Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Spectral-Based Graph Neural Networks for Complementary Item
  Recommendation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Modeling complementary relationships greatly helps recommender systems to
accurately and promptly recommend the subsequent items when one item is
purchased. Unlike traditional similar relationships, items with complementary
relationships may be purchased successively (such as iPhone and Airpods Pro),
and they not only share relevance but also exhibit dissimilarity. Since the two
attributes are opposites, modeling complementary relationships is challenging.
Previous attempts to exploit these relationships have either ignored or
oversimplified the dissimilarity attribute, resulting in ineffective modeling
and an inability to balance the two attributes. Since Graph Neural Networks
(GNNs) can capture the relevance and dissimilarity between nodes in the
spectral domain, we can leverage spectral-based GNNs to effectively understand
and model complementary relationships. In this study, we present a novel
approach called Spectral-based Complementary Graph Neural Networks (SComGNN)
that utilizes the spectral properties of complementary item graphs. We make the
first observation that complementary relationships consist of low-frequency and
mid-frequency components, corresponding to the relevance and dissimilarity
attributes, respectively. Based on this spectral observation, we design
spectral graph convolutional networks with low-pass and mid-pass filters to
capture the low-frequency and mid-frequency components. Additionally, we
propose a two-stage attention mechanism to adaptively integrate and balance the
two attributes. Experimental results on four e-commerce datasets demonstrate
the effectiveness of our model, with SComGNN significantly outperforming
existing baseline models.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haitong Luo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuying Meng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Suhang Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hanyun Cao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weiyao Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yequan Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yujun Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Accepted by AAAI-24</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02130v4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02130v4" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02131v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:32:38Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:32:38Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Synergistic interplays between the selective electron-phonon coupling,
  antiferromagnetic fluctuations and charge density wave in the YBa2Cu3Ox
  cuprate superconductor</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This research aims to investigate the synergistic effect between charge
density wave, selective electron-phonon coupling under antiferromagnetic
fluctuations, as well as the unusual electron distribution observed in ARPES
data in YBa2Cu3Ox superconductors (YBCO). By considering their synergistic
impact, our model can calculate the superconducting transition temperature Tc
of YBa2Cu3Ox as a function of pressure for x = 6.5 and 7 at a reasonable level.
Moreover, we have identified a specific antiferromagnetic phonon that
contributes significantly to the high Tc observed in YBCO. This finding
highlights the significance of these effects in achieving high Tc values. Our
study not only identifies an imbalanced charge-density wave effect for
triggering selective electron-phonon coupling but also explains why the charge
density wave usually occurs around the magnetic copper atoms. Furthermore, our
research reveals limitations in the conventional mean-field ab-initio
approximation used for antiferromagnetic fluctuations in YBCO. It shows that
the dynamic behavior of electrons in YBCO might not be accurately captured by
this approximation, as non-uniform magnetic fields under antiferromagnetic
fluctuations induce an additional electric potential on electrons across the
boundary between non-magnetic to magnetic sites instantaneously. This
instantaneous electric potential, in turn, suggest that the influence of the
antiferromagnetic phonon-based pairing mechanism might not have been optimized
in theory
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chi Ho Wong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rolf Lortz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02131v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02131v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02132v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:34:16Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:34:16Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>DCR-Consistency: Divide-Conquer-Reasoning for Consistency Evaluation and
  Improvement of Large Language Models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Evaluating the quality and variability of text generated by Large Language
Models (LLMs) poses a significant, yet unresolved research challenge.
Traditional evaluation methods, such as ROUGE and BERTScore, which measure
token similarity, often fail to capture the holistic semantic equivalence. This
results in a low correlation with human judgments and intuition, which is
especially problematic in high-stakes applications like healthcare and finance
where reliability, safety, and robust decision-making are highly critical. This
work proposes DCR, an automated framework for evaluating and improving the
consistency of LLM-generated texts using a divide-conquer-reasoning approach.
Unlike existing LLM-based evaluators that operate at the paragraph level, our
method employs a divide-and-conquer evaluator (DCE) that breaks down the
paragraph-to-paragraph comparison between two generated responses into
individual sentence-to-paragraph comparisons, each evaluated based on
predefined criteria. To facilitate this approach, we introduce an automatic
metric converter (AMC) that translates the output from DCE into an
interpretable numeric score. Beyond the consistency evaluation, we further
present a reason-assisted improver (RAI) that leverages the analytical reasons
with explanations identified by DCE to generate new responses aimed at reducing
these inconsistencies. Through comprehensive and systematic empirical analysis,
we show that our approach outperforms state-of-the-art methods by a large
margin (e.g., +19.3% and +24.3% on the SummEval dataset) in evaluating the
consistency of LLM generation across multiple benchmarks in semantic, factual,
and summarization consistency tasks. Our approach also substantially reduces
nearly 90% of output inconsistencies, showing promise for effective
hallucination mitigation.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wendi Cui</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiaxin Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhuohang Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lopez Damien</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kamalika Das</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bradley Malin</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sricharan Kumar</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02132v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02132v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02133v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-05-06T02:24:57Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:35:38Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Weak effects of electron-phonon interactions on the lattice thermal
  conductivity of wurtzite GaN with high electron concentrations</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Wurtzite gallium nitride (GaN) has great potential for high-frequency and
high-power applications due to its excellent electrical and thermal transport
properties. However, enhancing the performance of GaN-based power electronics
relies on heavy doping. Previous studies showed that electron-phonon
interactions have strong effects on the lattice thermal conductivity of GaN due
to the Fr\"ohlich interaction. Surprisingly, our investigation reveals weak
effects of electron-phonon interactions on the lattice thermal conductivity of
n-type GaN at ultra-high electron concentrations and the impact of the
Fr\"ohlich interaction can be ignored. The small phonon-electron scattering
rate is attributed to the limited scattering channels, quantified by the Fermi
surface nesting function. In contrast, there is a significant reduction in the
lattice thermal conductivity of p-type GaN at high hole concentrations due to
the relatively larger Fermi surface nesting function. Meanwhile, as p-type GaN
has relatively smaller electron-phonon matrix elements, the reduction in
lattice thermal conductivity is still weaker than that observed in p-type
silicon. Our work provides a deep understanding of thermal transport in doped
GaN and the conclusions can be further extended to other wide-bandgap
semiconductors, including $\beta$-Ga2O3, AlN, and ZnO.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jianshi Sun</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shouhang Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhen Tong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cheng Shao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiangchuan Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Qianqian Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yucheng Xiong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Meng An</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiangjun Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02133v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02133v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02134v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:35:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:35:43Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Female Entrepreneur on Board:Assessing the Effect of Gender on Corporate
  Financial Constraints</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This study investigates the impact of female leadership on the financial
constraints of firms, which are publicly listed entrepreneurial enterprises in
China. Utilizing data from 938 companies on the China Growth Enterprise Market
(GEM) over a period of 2013-2022, this paper explores how the female presence
in CEO positions, senior management, and board membership influences a firm's
ability to manage financial constraints. Our analysis employs the
Kaplan-Zingales (KZ) Index to measure these constraints, encompassing some key
financial factors such as cash flow, dividends, and leverage. The findings
reveal that companies with female CEOs or a higher proportion of women in top
management are associated with reduced financial constraints. However, the
influence of female board members is less clear-cut. Our study also delves into
the variances of these effects between high-tech and low-tech industry sectors,
emphasizing how internal gender biases in high-tech industries may impede the
alleviation of financing constraints on firms. This research contributes to a
nuanced understanding of the role of gender dynamics in corporate financial
management, especially in the context of China's evolving economic landscape.
It underscores the importance of promoting female leadership not only for
gender equity but also for enhancing corporate financial resilience.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ruiying Xiao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02134v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02134v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="q-fin.EC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02460v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-04-03T22:23:25Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:39:13Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Improved Zero-Shot Classification by Adapting VLMs with Text
  Descriptions</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The zero-shot performance of existing vision-language models (VLMs) such as
CLIP is limited by the availability of large-scale, aligned image and text
datasets in specific domains. In this work, we leverage two complementary
sources of information -- descriptions of categories generated by large
language models (LLMs) and abundant, fine-grained image classification datasets
-- to improve the zero-shot classification performance of VLMs across
fine-grained domains. On the technical side, we develop methods to train VLMs
with this "bag-level" image-text supervision. We find that simply using these
attributes at test-time does not improve performance, but our training
strategy, for example, on the iNaturalist dataset, leads to an average
improvement of 4-5% in zero-shot classification accuracy for novel categories
of birds and flowers. Similar improvements are observed in domains where a
subset of the categories was used to fine-tune the model. By prompting LLMs in
various ways, we generate descriptions that capture visual appearance, habitat,
and geographic regions and pair them with existing attributes such as the
taxonomic structure of the categories. We systematically evaluate their ability
to improve zero-shot categorization in natural domains. Our findings suggest
that geographic priors can be just as effective and are complementary to visual
appearance. Our method also outperforms prior work on prompt-based tuning of
VLMs. We release the benchmark, consisting of 14 datasets at
https://github.com/cvl-umass/AdaptCLIPZS , which will contribute to future
research in zero-shot recognition.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Oindrila Saha</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Grant Van Horn</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Subhransu Maji</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02460v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02460v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02135v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:39:49Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:39:49Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>PosCUDA: Position based Convolution for Unlearnable Audio Datasets</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Deep learning models require large amounts of clean data to acheive good
performance. To avoid the cost of expensive data acquisition, researchers use
the abundant data available on the internet. This raises significant privacy
concerns on the potential misuse of personal data for model training without
authorisation. Recent works such as CUDA propose solutions to this problem by
adding class-wise blurs to make datasets unlearnable, i.e a model can never use
the acquired dataset for learning. However these methods often reduce the
quality of the data making it useless for practical applications. We introduce
PosCUDA, a position based convolution for creating unlearnable audio datasets.
PosCUDA uses class-wise convolutions on small patches of audio. The location of
the patches are based on a private key for each class, hence the model learns
the relations between positional blurs and labels, while failing to generalize.
We empirically show that PosCUDA can achieve unlearnability while maintaining
the quality of the original audio datasets. Our proposed method is also robust
to different audio feature representations such as MFCC, raw audio and
different architectures such as transformers, convolutional networks etc.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Vignesh Gokul</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shlomo Dubnov</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02135v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02135v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02461v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:41:13Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:41:13Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Boundary Controllability of Riemann-Liouville Fractional Semilinear
  Equations</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We study the boundary regional controllability of a class of
Riemann-Liouville fractional semilinear sub-diffusion systems with boundary
Neumann conditions. The result is obtained by using semi-group theory, the
fractional Hilbert uniqueness method, and Schauder's fixed point theorem.
Conditions on the order of the derivative, internal region, and on the
nonlinear part are obtained. Furthermore, we present appropriate sufficient
conditions for the considered fractional system to be regionally controllable
and, therefore, boundary regionally controllable. An example of a population
density system with diffusion is given to illustrate the obtained theoretical
results. Numerical simulations show that the proposed method provides
satisfying results regarding two cases of the control operator.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Asmae Tajani</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fatima-Zahrae El Alaoui</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Delfim F. M. Torres</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1016/j.cnsns.2023.107814</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cnsns.2023.107814" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>This is a preprint version of the paper published open access in
  'Commun. Nonlinear Sci. Numer. Simul.'
  [https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cnsns.2023.107814]. Submitted 26/Jul/2022; Revised
  08/Dec/2022 and 16/Oct/2023; Accepted for publication 30/Dec/2023; Available
  online 03/Jan/2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns2:journal_ref>Commun. Nonlinear Sci. Numer. Simul. 131 (2024), Art. 107814, 11
  pp</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02461v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02461v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02136v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:41:52Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:41:52Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>$L^p$-spectral theory for the Laplacian on forms</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this article, we find sufficient conditions on an open Riemannian manifold
so that a Weyl criterion holds for the $L^p$-spectrum of the Laplacian on
$k$-forms, and also prove the decomposition of the $L^p$-spectrum depending on
the order of the forms. We then show that the resolvent set of an operator such
as the Laplacian on $L^p$ lies outside a parabola whenever the volume of the
manifold has an exponential volume growth rate, removing the requirement on the
manifold to be of bounded geometry. We conclude by providing a detailed
description of the $L^p$ spectrum of the Laplacian on $k$-forms over hyperbolic
space.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nelia Charalambous</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiqin Lu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02136v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02136v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.AP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="58J50" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02137v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:42:36Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:42:36Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>SyCoCa: Symmetrizing Contrastive Captioners with Attentive Masking for
  Multimodal Alignment</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Multimodal alignment between language and vision is the fundamental topic in
current vision-language model research. Contrastive Captioners (CoCa), as a
representative method, integrates Contrastive Language-Image Pretraining (CLIP)
and Image Caption (IC) into a unified framework, resulting in impressive
results. CLIP imposes a bidirectional constraints on global representation of
entire images and sentences. Although IC conducts an unidirectional
image-to-text generation on local representation, it lacks any constraint on
local text-to-image reconstruction, which limits the ability to understand
images at a fine-grained level when aligned with texts. To achieve multimodal
alignment from both global and local perspectives, this paper proposes
Symmetrizing Contrastive Captioners (SyCoCa), which introduces bidirectional
interactions on images and texts across the global and local representation
levels. Specifically, we expand a Text-Guided Masked Image Modeling (TG-MIM)
head based on ITC and IC heads. The improved SyCoCa can further leverage
textual cues to reconstruct contextual images and visual cues to predict
textual contents. When implementing bidirectional local interactions, the local
contents of images tend to be cluttered or unrelated to their textual
descriptions. Thus, we employ an attentive masking strategy to select effective
image patches for interaction. Extensive experiments on five vision-language
tasks, including image-text retrieval, image-captioning, visual question
answering, and zero-shot/finetuned image classification, validate the
effectiveness of our proposed method.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ziping Ma</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Furong Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jian Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ming Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Qingpei Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02137v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02137v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02138v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:43:41Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:43:41Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Explore Human Parsing Modality for Action Recognition</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Multimodal-based action recognition methods have achieved high success using
pose and RGB modality. However, skeletons sequences lack appearance depiction
and RGB images suffer irrelevant noise due to modality limitations. To address
this, we introduce human parsing feature map as a novel modality, since it can
selectively retain effective semantic features of the body parts, while
filtering out most irrelevant noise. We propose a new dual-branch framework
called Ensemble Human Parsing and Pose Network (EPP-Net), which is the first to
leverage both skeletons and human parsing modalities for action recognition.
The first human pose branch feeds robust skeletons in graph convolutional
network to model pose features, while the second human parsing branch also
leverages depictive parsing feature maps to model parsing festures via
convolutional backbones. The two high-level features will be effectively
combined through a late fusion strategy for better action recognition.
Extensive experiments on NTU RGB+D and NTU RGB+D 120 benchmarks consistently
verify the effectiveness of our proposed EPP-Net, which outperforms the
existing action recognition methods. Our code is available at:
https://github.com/liujf69/EPP-Net-Action.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jinfu Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Runwei Ding</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuhang Wen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nan Dai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fanyang Meng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shen Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mengyuan Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:2307.07977</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02138v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02138v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02139v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:44:05Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:44:05Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Airport service quality perception and flight delays: examining the
  influence of psychosituational latent traits of respondents in passenger
  satisfaction surveys</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The service quality of a passenger transport operator can be measured through
face-to-face surveys at the terminals or on board. However, the resulting
responses may suffer from the influence of the intrinsic aspects of the
respondent's personality and emotional context at the time of the interview.
This study proposes a methodology to generate and select control variables for
these latent psychosituational traits, thus mitigating the risk of omitted
variable bias. We developed an econometric model of the determinants of
passenger satisfaction in a survey conducted at the largest airport in Latin
America, S\~ao Paulo GRU Airport. Our focus was on the role of flight delays in
the perception of quality. The results of this study confirm the existence of a
relationship between flight delays and the global satisfaction of passengers
with airports. In addition, favorable evaluations regarding airports'
food/beverage concessions and Wi-Fi services, but not their retail options,
have a relevant moderating effect on that relationship. Furthermore,
dissatisfaction arising from passengers' interaction with the airline can have
negative spillover effects on their satisfaction with the airport. We also
found evidence of blame-attribution behavior, in which only delays of internal
origin, such as failures in flight management, are significant, indicating that
passengers overlook weather-related flight delays. Finally, the results suggest
that an empirical specification that does not consider the latent
psychosituational traits of passengers produces a relevant overestimation of
the absolute effect of flight delays on passenger satisfaction.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alessandro V. M. Oliveira</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bruno F. Oliveira</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Moises D. Vassallo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1016/j.retrec.2023.101371</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.retrec.2023.101371" rel="related" />
    <ns2:journal_ref>Research in Transportation Economics (2023), 102, 101371</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02139v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02139v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="econ.GN" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="q-fin.EC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10905v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:45:33Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:45:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Observations of Orbiting Hot Spots around Scalarized
  Reissner-Nordström Black Holes</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This paper investigates the observational signatures of hot spots orbiting
scalarized Reissner-Nordstr\"om black holes, which have been reported to
possess multiple photon spheres. In contrast to the single-photon sphere case,
hot spots orbiting black holes with two photon spheres produce additional image
tracks in time integrated images capturing a complete orbit of hot spots.
Notably, these newly observed patterns manifest as a distinct second-highest
peak in temporal magnitudes when observed at low inclination angles. These
findings offer promising observational probes for distinguishing black holes
with multiple photon spheres from their single-photon sphere counterparts.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yiqian Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Peng Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haitang Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>22 pages, 5 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10905v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.10905v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02140v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:45:53Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:45:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Exploring the Unconventional Electron Distribution Patterns in
  Iron-based Superconductors</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  For more than a decade, the unusual distribution of electrons observed in
ARPES (angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy) data within the energy range
of ~30meV to ~300meV below the Fermi level, known as the ARPES range, has
remained a puzzle in the field of iron-based superconductivity. However, in
this study, we have made a noteworthy observation: although the electron-phonon
coupling alone is insufficient to account for the observed ARPES pattern, our
analysis reveals that when the instantaneous electron-phonon coupling occurring
in selective phonon channel is enhanced by the coexistence of antiferromagnetic
spin density wave and charge density wave phenomena, the amplified interaction
becomes comparable to the ARPES range. This finding suggests that the
instantaneous interplay between these intricate phenomena should play a crucial
role in generating the observed energy range in ARPES. Our work may provide a
valuable clue towards achieving a deeper understanding of the complex
relationship between electronic correlations, lattice structure, and
superconductivity in iron-based materials for uncovering the origin of the
unconventional ARPES pattern.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chi Ho Wong</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rolf Lortz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02140v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02140v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.supr-con" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02141v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-10-04T13:29:14Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:46:39Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Bayesian Unsupervised Disentanglement of Anatomy and Geometry for Deep
  Groupwise Image Registration</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This article presents a general Bayesian learning framework for multi-modal
groupwise image registration. The method builds on probabilistic modelling of
the image generative process, where the underlying common anatomy and geometric
variations of the observed images are explicitly disentangled as latent
variables. Therefore, groupwise image registration is achieved via hierarchical
Bayesian inference. We propose a novel hierarchical variational auto-encoding
architecture to realise the inference procedure of the latent variables, where
the registration parameters can be explicitly estimated in a mathematically
interpretable fashion. Remarkably, this new paradigm learns groupwise image
registration in an unsupervised closed-loop self-reconstruction process,
sparing the burden of designing complex image-based similarity measures. The
computationally efficient disentangled network architecture is also inherently
scalable and flexible, allowing for groupwise registration on large-scale image
groups with variable sizes. Furthermore, the inferred structural
representations from multi-modal images via disentanglement learning are
capable of capturing the latent anatomy of the observations with visual
semantics. Extensive experiments were conducted to validate the proposed
framework, including four different datasets from cardiac, brain, and abdominal
medical images. The results have demonstrated the superiority of our method
over conventional similarity-based approaches in terms of accuracy, efficiency,
scalability, and interpretability.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xinzhe Luo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xin Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Linda Shapiro</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chun Yuan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jianfeng Feng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiahai Zhuang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02141v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02141v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02142v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-06T03:17:55Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:48:21Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>GUESS:GradUally Enriching SyntheSis for Text-Driven Human Motion
  Generation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this paper, we propose a novel cascaded diffusion-based generative
framework for text-driven human motion synthesis, which exploits a strategy
named GradUally Enriching SyntheSis (GUESS as its abbreviation). The strategy
sets up generation objectives by grouping body joints of detailed skeletons in
close semantic proximity together and then replacing each of such joint group
with a single body-part node. Such an operation recursively abstracts a human
pose to coarser and coarser skeletons at multiple granularity levels. With
gradually increasing the abstraction level, human motion becomes more and more
concise and stable, significantly benefiting the cross-modal motion synthesis
task. The whole text-driven human motion synthesis problem is then divided into
multiple abstraction levels and solved with a multi-stage generation framework
with a cascaded latent diffusion model: an initial generator first generates
the coarsest human motion guess from a given text description; then, a series
of successive generators gradually enrich the motion details based on the
textual description and the previous synthesized results. Notably, we further
integrate GUESS with the proposed dynamic multi-condition fusion mechanism to
dynamically balance the cooperative effects of the given textual condition and
synthesized coarse motion prompt in different generation stages. Extensive
experiments on large-scale datasets verify that GUESS outperforms existing
state-of-the-art methods by large margins in terms of accuracy, realisticness,
and diversity. Code is available at https://github.com/Xuehao-Gao/GUESS.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuehao Gao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yang Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhenyu Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shaoyi Du</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhongqian Sun</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yang Wu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Accepted by IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics
  (2024)</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02142v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02142v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02143v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:49:10Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:49:10Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Graph Neural Networks for Tabular Data Learning: A Survey with Taxonomy
  and Directions</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this survey, we dive into Tabular Data Learning (TDL) using Graph Neural
Networks (GNNs), a domain where deep learning-based approaches have
increasingly shown superior performance in both classification and regression
tasks compared to traditional methods. The survey highlights a critical gap in
deep neural TDL methods: the underrepresentation of latent correlations among
data instances and feature values. GNNs, with their innate capability to model
intricate relationships and interactions between diverse elements of tabular
data, have garnered significant interest and application across various TDL
domains. Our survey provides a systematic review of the methods involved in
designing and implementing GNNs for TDL (GNN4TDL). It encompasses a detailed
investigation into the foundational aspects and an overview of GNN-based TDL
methods, offering insights into their evolving landscape. We present a
comprehensive taxonomy focused on constructing graph structures and
representation learning within GNN-based TDL methods. In addition, the survey
examines various training plans, emphasizing the integration of auxiliary tasks
to enhance the effectiveness of instance representations. A critical part of
our discussion is dedicated to the practical application of GNNs across a
spectrum of GNN4TDL scenarios, demonstrating their versatility and impact.
Lastly, we discuss the limitations and propose future research directions,
aiming to spur advancements in GNN4TDL. This survey serves as a resource for
researchers and practitioners, offering a thorough understanding of GNNs' role
in revolutionizing TDL and pointing towards future innovations in this
promising area.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cheng-Te Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yu-Che Tsai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chih-Yao Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jay Chiehen Liao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Under review, ongoing work, Github page:
  https://github.com/Roytsai27/awesome-GNN4TDL</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02143v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02143v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02144v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:49:50Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:49:50Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>The Radcliffe wave parameters from data on open star clusters</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  A spectral analysis of the vertical positions and velocities of 374 open star
clusters (OSCs) was carried out. We took these OSCs from the Hunt, Reffert
catalog; they have an average age of about 10 million years, and are located on
the galactic plane XY in a narrow zone inclined by 25 degrees to the galactic
axis Y. The following estimates of the parameters of the Radcliffe wave were
obtained: a) the maximum value in periodic perturbations of vertical
coordinates $Z_{max}=92\pm10$ pc with the wavelength of these perturbations
$\lambda_z=4.82\pm0.09$ kpc; b)~maximum value of the velocity of vertical
disturbances $W_{max}=4.36\pm0.12$ km s$^{-1}$ with disturbance wavelength
$\lambda_W=1.78\pm0.02$ kpc. Note that the results of the vertical velocity
analysis are first-class in accuracy and completely new.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Vadim V. Bobylev</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Anisa T. Bajkova</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1088/1674-4527/ad113f</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1674-4527/ad113f" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>6 pages, 3 figures, Accepted to RAA</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02144v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02144v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02145v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:51:16Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:51:16Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>ED: Perceptually tuned Enhanced Compression Model</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This paper summarises the design of the candidate ED for the Challenge on
Learned Image Compression 2024. This candidate aims at providing an anchor
based on conventional coding technologies to the learning-based approaches
mostly targeted in the challenge.
  The proposed candidate is based on the Enhanced Compression Model (ECM)
developed at JVET, the Joint Video Experts Team of ITU-T VCEG and ISO/IEC MPEG.
  Here, ECM is adapted to the challenge objective: to maximise the perceived
quality, the encoding is performed according to a perceptual metric, also the
sequence selection is performed in a perceptual manner to fit the target bit
per pixel objectives.
  The primary objective of this candidate is to assess the recent developments
in video coding standardisation and in parallel to evaluate the progress made
by learning-based techniques. To this end, this paper explains how to generate
coded images fulfilling the challenge requirements, in a reproducible way,
targeting the maximum performance.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pierrick Philippe</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Théo Ladune</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Stéphane Davenet</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thomas Leguay</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Challenge on Learned Image Compression (CLIC), DCC2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02145v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02145v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02146v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-07-28T06:24:02Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:51:19Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Masses and Magnetic Moments of Singly Heavy Pentaquarks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Motivated by the recent discovery of single heavy tetraquark structures,
$T_{c\bar{s}0}^a (2900)^{++}$ and $T_{c\bar{s}0}^a(2900)^0$ by the LHCb
collaboration, masses and magnetic moments of singly heavy pentaquark states
are estimated in this work. To classify the singly heavy pentaquark structures,
we employ the special unitary representation. By using the SU(3) flavor
representation, we placed singly heavy pentaquark states into the allowed
flavor multiples. Also, by using the extension of the Gursey-Radicati mass
formula and the effective mass scheme, we estimated the masses of singly heavy
pentaquark states. Further, magnetic moments of these states have been
calculated using the effective mass and the screened charge techniques. A
thorough comparison of our results shows reasonable agreement with the
available theoretical data and may be helpful for future experimental studies.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ankush Sharma</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alka Upadhyay</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1007/s00601-025-01986-w</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00601-025-01986-w" rel="related" />
    <ns2:journal_ref>Few-Body Syst 66, 14 (2025)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02146v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02146v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02147v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:53:08Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:53:08Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Exploring Boundary of GPT-4V on Marine Analysis: A Preliminary Case
  Study</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Large language models (LLMs) have demonstrated a powerful ability to answer
various queries as a general-purpose assistant. The continuous multi-modal
large language models (MLLM) empower LLMs with the ability to perceive visual
signals. The launch of GPT-4 (Generative Pre-trained Transformers) has
generated significant interest in the research communities. GPT-4V(ison) has
demonstrated significant power in both academia and industry fields, as a focal
point in a new artificial intelligence generation. Though significant success
was achieved by GPT-4V, exploring MLLMs in domain-specific analysis (e.g.,
marine analysis) that required domain-specific knowledge and expertise has
gained less attention. In this study, we carry out the preliminary and
comprehensive case study of utilizing GPT-4V for marine analysis. This report
conducts a systematic evaluation of existing GPT-4V, assessing the performance
of GPT-4V on marine research and also setting a new standard for future
developments in MLLMs. The experimental results of GPT-4V show that the
responses generated by GPT-4V are still far away from satisfying the
domain-specific requirements of the marine professions. All images and prompts
used in this study will be available at
https://github.com/hkust-vgd/Marine_GPT-4V_Eval
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ziqiang Zheng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yiwei Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jipeng Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tuan-Anh Vu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Huimin Zeng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yue Him Wong Tim</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sai-Kit Yeung</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>51 pages, 36 figures, Repository:
  https://github.com/hkust-vgd/Marine_GPT-4V_Eval</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02147v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02147v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02148v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:53:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:53:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Multiple power-law tails in the density and column-density distribution
  in contracting star-forming clumps</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We present a numerical study of the evolution of power-law tails (PLTs) in
the (column-)density distributions ($N$-PDF, $\rho$-PDF) in contracting
star-forming clumps in primordial gas, without and with some initial rotational
and/or turbulent support. In all considered runs multiple PLTs emerge shortly
after the formation of the first protostar. The first PLT (PLT 1) in the
$\rho$-PDF is a stable feature with slope $q_1\simeq -1.3$ which corresponds --
under the condition of preserved spherical symmetry -- to the outer envelope of
the protostellar object with density profile $\rho\propto l^{-2}$ in the
classical Larson-Penston collapse model, where $l$ is the radius. The second
PLT (PLT 2) in the $\rho$-PDF is stable in the pure-infall runs but fluctuates
significantly in the runs with initial support against gravity as dozens of
protostars form and their mutual tidal forces change the density structure. Its
mean slope, $\langle q_2\rangle\simeq -2$, corresponds to a density profile of
$\rho\propto l^{-3/2}$ which describes a core in free fall in the classical
Larson-Penston collapse model or an attractor solution at scales with
dominating protostellar gravity. PLT 1 and PLT 2 in the $N$-PDFs are generally
consistent with the observational data of Galactic low-mass star-forming
regions from {\it Herschel} data. In the runs with initial support against
gravity a third PLT (PLT~3) in the $\rho$-PDFs appears simultaneously with or
after the emergence of PLT 2. It is very shallow, with mean slope of $\langle
q_3\rangle\simeq -1$, and is associated with the formation of thin protostellar
accretion disks.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Todor V. Veltchev</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Philipp Girichidis</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lyubov Marinkova</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sava Donkov</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Orlin Stanchev</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ralf S. Klessen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>14 pages, 12 figures; accepted for publication in MNRAS (main
  journal)</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02148v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02148v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="astro-ph.GA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02149v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:53:51Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:53:51Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>AGuIX nanoparticle-nanobody bioconjugates to target immune checkpoint
  receptors</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Comparison of click chemistry and sortagging grafting strategies for
functionalizing AGuIX nanoparticles with nanobodies to develop a tri-functional
technology combining MRI imaging, radiotherapy, and immunotherapy by inhibiting
immune checkpoints.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Léna Carmès</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Guillaume Bort</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM, IUF</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>François Lux</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM, IUF</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Léa Seban</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Paul Rocchi</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zeinaf Muradova</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>TechSep</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Agnès Hagège</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>TechSep</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Laurence Heinrich-Balard</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>MATEIS</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Frédéric Delolme</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>BIOMAPS</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Virginie Gueguen-Chaignon</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>BIOMAPS</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Charles Truillet</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>BIOMAPS</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Stephanie Crowley</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Elisa Bello</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tristan Doussineau</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael Dougan</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Olivier Tillement</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ILM</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jonathan Schoenfeld</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Needa Brown</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ross Berbeco</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1039/D3NR04777F</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/D3NR04777F" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>Nanoscale, 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02149v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02149v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.bio-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.bio-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01646v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:55:53Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:55:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Recommendations for public action towards sustainable generative AI
  systems</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Growing awareness of the environmental impact of digital technologies has led
to several isolated initiatives to promote sustainable practices. However,
despite these efforts, the environmental footprint of generative AI,
particularly in terms of greenhouse gas emissions and water consumption,
remains considerable. This contribution first presents the components of this
environmental footprint, highlighting the massive CO2 emissions and water
consumption associated with training large language models, thus underlining
the need to rethink learning and inference methods. The paper also explores the
factors and characteristics of models that have an influence on their
environmental footprint and demonstrates the existence of solutions to reduce
it, such as using more efficient processors or optimising the energy
performance of data centres. The potentially harmful effects of AI on the
planet and its ecosystem have made environmental protection one of the founding
principles of AI ethics at international and European levels. However, this
recognition has not yet translated into concrete measures to address it.To
address this issue, our contribution puts forward twelve pragmatic
recommendations for public action to promote sustainable generative AI, in
particular by building a long-term strategy to achieve carbon neutrality for AI
models, encouraging international cooperation to set common standards,
supporting scientific research and developing appropriate legal and regulatory
frameworks.This paper seeks to inform the members of the Interministerial
Committee on Generative AI about the environmental challenges of this
technology by providing a brief review of the scientific literature on the
subject and proposing concrete recommendations of public policy actions to
reconcile technological innovation with the need to protect our environment.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thomas Le Goff</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>EDF</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>in French language</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01646v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2402.01646v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02462v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:57:06Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:57:06Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Remaining-lifetime age-structured branching processes</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We study age-structured branching models with reproduction law depending on
the remaining lifetime of the parent. The lifespan of an individual is decided
at its birth and its remaining lifetime decreases at the unit speed. The models
without or with immigration are constructed as measure-valued processes by
pathwise unique solutions of stochastic equations driven by time-space Poisson
random measures. In the subcritical branching case, we give a sufficient
condition for the ergodicity of the process with immigration. Two large number
laws and a central limit theorem of the occupation times are proved.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ziling Cheng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zenghu Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02462v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02462v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02150v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-09-30T06:49:33Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:57:09Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Marginal Debiased Network for Fair Visual Recognition</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Deep neural networks (DNNs) are often prone to learn the spurious
correlations between target classes and bias attributes, like gender and race,
inherent in a major portion of training data (bias-aligned samples), thus
showing unfair behavior and arising controversy in the modern pluralistic and
egalitarian society. In this paper, we propose a novel marginal debiased
network (MDN) to learn debiased representations. More specifically, a marginal
softmax loss (MSL) is designed by introducing the idea of margin penalty into
the fairness problem, which assigns a larger margin for bias-conflicting
samples (data without spurious correlations) than for bias-aligned ones, so as
to deemphasize the spurious correlations and improve generalization on unbiased
test criteria. To determine the margins, our MDN is optimized through a meta
learning framework. We propose a meta equalized loss (MEL) to perceive the
model fairness, and adaptively update the margin parameters by
meta-optimization which requires the trained model guided by the optimal
margins should minimize MEL computed on an unbiased meta-validation set.
Extensive experiments on BiasedMNIST, Corrupted CIFAR-10, CelebA and UTK-Face
datasets demonstrate that our MDN can achieve a remarkable performance on
under-represented samples and obtain superior debiased results against the
previous approaches.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mei Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weihong Deng</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiani Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sen Su</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02150v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02150v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02151v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T08:58:25Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T08:58:25Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Frequency-Adaptive Pan-Sharpening with Mixture of Experts</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Pan-sharpening involves reconstructing missing high-frequency information in
multi-spectral images with low spatial resolution, using a higher-resolution
panchromatic image as guidance. Although the inborn connection with frequency
domain, existing pan-sharpening research has not almost investigated the
potential solution upon frequency domain. To this end, we propose a novel
Frequency Adaptive Mixture of Experts (FAME) learning framework for
pan-sharpening, which consists of three key components: the Adaptive Frequency
Separation Prediction Module, the Sub-Frequency Learning Expert Module, and the
Expert Mixture Module. In detail, the first leverages the discrete cosine
transform to perform frequency separation by predicting the frequency mask. On
the basis of generated mask, the second with low-frequency MOE and
high-frequency MOE takes account for enabling the effective low-frequency and
high-frequency information reconstruction. Followed by, the final fusion module
dynamically weights high-frequency and low-frequency MOE knowledge to adapt to
remote sensing images with significant content variations. Quantitative and
qualitative experiments over multiple datasets demonstrate that our method
performs the best against other state-of-the-art ones and comprises a strong
generalization ability for real-world scenes. Code will be made publicly at
\url{https://github.com/alexhe101/FAME-Net}.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuanhua He</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Keyu Yan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rui Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chengjun Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jie Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Man Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02151v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02151v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02463v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:02:59Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:02:59Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Some clues to build a sound analysis relevant to hearing</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Analysis tools used in research laboratories, for sound synthesis, by
musicians or sound engineers can be rather different. Discussion of the
assumptions and of the limitations of these tools permits to propose a first
tool as relevant and versatile as possible for all the sound actors with a
major aim: one must be able to listen to each element of the analysis because
hearing is the final reference tool. This tool should also be used, in the
future, to reinvestigate the definition of sound (or Acoustics) on the basis of
some recent works on musical instrument modeling, speech production and
loudspeakers design. Audio illustrations will be given.Paper 6041 presented at
the 116th Convention of the Audio Engineering Society, Berlin, 2004
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Laurent Millot</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>ACTE</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:journal_ref>116th Convention of the Audio Engineering Society,, Audio
  Engineering Society, May 2004, Berlin (Germany), Germany</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02463v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02463v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02152v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:04:16Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:04:16Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Estimating continuous data of wrist joint angles using ultrasound images</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Ultrasound imaging has recently been introduced as a sensing interface for
joint motion estimation. The use of ultrasound images as an estimation method
is expected to improve the control performance of assistive devices and
human--machine interfaces. This study aimed to estimate continuous wrist joint
angles using ultrasound images. Specifically, in an experiment, joint angle
information was obtained during extension--flexion movements, and ultrasound
images of the associated muscles were acquired. Using the features obtained
from ultrasound images, a multivariate linear regression model was used to
estimate the joint angles. The coordinates of the feature points obtained using
optical flow from the ultrasound images were used as explanatory variables of
the multivariate linear regression model. The model was trained and tested for
each trial by each participant to verify the estimation accuracy. The results
show that the mean and standard deviation of the estimation accuracy for all
trials were root mean square error (RMSE)=1.82 $\pm$ 0.54 deg and coefficient
of determination (R2)=0.985 $\pm$ 0.009. Our method achieves a highly accurate
estimation of joint angles compared with previous studies using other signals,
such as surface electromyography, while the multivariate linear regression
model is simple and both computational and model training costs are low.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yo Kobayashi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yoshihiro Katagi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02152v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02152v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.SP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02153v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:04:54Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:04:54Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Unit Testing in ASP Revisited: Language and Test-Driven Development
  Environment</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Unit testing frameworks are nowadays considered a best practice, included in
almost all modern software development processes, to achieve rapid development
of correct specifications. Knowledge representation and reasoning paradigms
such as Answer Set Programming (ASP), that have been used in industry-level
applications, are not an exception. Indeed, the first unit testing
specification language for ASP was proposed in 2011 as a feature of the ASPIDE
development environment. Later, a more portable unit testing language was
included in the LANA annotation language. In this paper we revisit both
languages and tools for unit testing in ASP. We propose a new unit test
specification language that allows one to inline tests within ASP programs, and
we identify the computational complexity of the tasks associated with checking
the various program-correctness assertions. Test-case specifications are
transparent to the traditional evaluation, but can be interpreted by a specific
testing tool. Thus, we present a novel environment supporting test driven
development of ASP programs.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Giovanni Amendola</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tobias Berei</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Giuseppe Mazzotta</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Francesco Ricca</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1017/S1471068424000103</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S1471068424000103" rel="related" />
    <ns2:journal_ref>Theory and Practice of Logic Programming 24 (2024) 1078-1108</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02153v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02153v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02154v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:05:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:05:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Disentangle Estimation of Causal Effects from Cross-Silo Data</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Estimating causal effects among different events is of great importance to
critical fields such as drug development. Nevertheless, the data features
associated with events may be distributed across various silos and remain
private within respective parties, impeding direct information exchange between
them. This, in turn, can result in biased estimations of local causal effects,
which rely on the characteristics of only a subset of the covariates. To tackle
this challenge, we introduce an innovative disentangle architecture designed to
facilitate the seamless cross-silo transmission of model parameters, enriched
with causal mechanisms, through a combination of shared and private branches.
Besides, we introduce global constraints into the equation to effectively
mitigate bias within the various missing domains, thereby elevating the
accuracy of our causal effect estimation. Extensive experiments conducted on
new semi-synthetic datasets show that our method outperforms state-of-the-art
baselines.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuxuan Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Haozhao Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shuang Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiming He</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenchao Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jialiang Zhu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fan Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Accepted by ICASSP 2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02154v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02154v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02155v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-12-13T17:28:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:06:11Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Asymptotically Optimal Proper Conflict-Free Colouring</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  A proper conflict-free colouring of a graph is a colouring of the vertices
such that any two adjacent vertices receive different colours, and for every
non-isolated vertex $v$, some colour appears exactly once on the neighbourhood
of $v$. Caro, Petru\v{s}evski and \v{S}krekovski conjectured that every
connected graph with maximum degree $\Delta \geq 3$ has a proper conflict-free
colouring with at most $\Delta+1$ colours. This conjecture holds for $\Delta=3$
and remains open for $\Delta \geq 4$. In this paper we prove that this
conjecture holds asymptotically; namely, every graph with maximum degree
$\Delta$ has a proper conflict-free colouring with $(1+o(1))\Delta$ colours.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chun-Hung Liu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Bruce Reed</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1002/rsa.21285</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/rsa.21285" rel="related" />
    <ns2:journal_ref>Random Structures Algorithms 66 (2025), e21285</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02155v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02155v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02156v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:08:14Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:08:14Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Cool-Chic: Perceptually Tuned Low Complexity Overfitted Image Coder</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This paper summarises the design of the Cool-Chic candidate for the Challenge
on Learned Image Compression. This candidate attempts to demonstrate that
neural coding methods can lead to low complexity and lightweight image decoders
while still offering competitive performance. The approach is based on the
already published overfitted lightweight neural networks Cool-Chic, further
adapted to the human subjective viewing targeted in this challenge.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Théo Ladune</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pierrick Philippe</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Gordon Clare</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Félix Henry</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thomas Leguay</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>Challenge on Learned Image Compression (CLIC), DCC2024</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02156v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02156v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02157v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:09:55Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:09:55Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>High-order compact gas-kinetic scheme in arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian
  formulation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This study proposes an extension of the high-order compact gas-kinetic scheme
(CGKS) to compressible flow simulation in an arbitrary Lagrangian-Eulerian
(ALE) formulation in unstructured mesh. The ALE method is achieved by
subdividing arbitrary mesh into tetrahedrons and integrating flux function in a
local coordinate system at the cell interface to ensure geometric conservation
law. The scheme incorporates a compact reconstruction with third-order accuracy
for updating both cell-averaged conservative flow variables and their
gradients. HWENO-type nonlinear reconstruction and gradient compression factors
are adopted to improve the accuracy and robustness of the scheme. A multi-stage
multi-derivative (MSMD) time-stepping method is also implemented to achieve
high-order time accuracy with fewer middle stages. The scheme is used to study
problems involving moving boundaries. The numerical experiments demonstrate the
effectiveness of the scheme in capturing the accurate solutions of both
low-speed smooth flow and highly compressible ones with strong shock waves.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yue Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kun Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02157v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02157v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02158v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:13:18Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:13:18Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Shayona@SMM4H23: COVID-19 Self diagnosis classification using BERT and
  LightGBM models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This paper describes approaches and results for shared Task 1 and 4 of
SMMH4-23 by Team Shayona. Shared Task-1 was binary classification of english
tweets self-reporting a COVID-19 diagnosis, and Shared Task-4 was Binary
classification of English Reddit posts self-reporting a social anxiety disorder
diagnosis. Our team has achieved the highest f1-score 0.94 in Task-1 among all
participants. We have leveraged the Transformer model (BERT) in combination
with the LightGBM model for both tasks.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rushi Chavda</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Darshan Makwana</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Vraj Patel</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Anupam Shukla</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02158v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02158v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02159v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:14:26Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:14:26Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Valley-Polarized quantum Hall phase in a strain-controlled Dirac system</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In multivalley systems, the valley pseudospin offers rich physics going from
encoding of information by its polarization (valleytronics), to exploring novel
phases of matter when its degeneracy is changed. Here, by strain engineering,
we reveal fully valley-polarized quantum Hall (QH) phases in the Pb1-xSnxSe
Dirac system. Remarkably, when the valley energy splitting exceeds the
fundamental band gap, we observe a bipolar QH phase, heralded by the
coexistence of hole and electron chiral edge states at distinct valleys in the
same quantum well. This suggests that spatially overlaid counter-propagating
chiral edge states emerging at different valleys do not interfere with each
other.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>G. Krizman</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>J. Bermejo-Ortiz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>T. Zakusylo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>M. Hajlaoui</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>T. Takashiro</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>M. Rosmus</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>N. Olszowska</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>J. J. Kolodziej</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>G. Bauer</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Y. Guldner</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>G. Springholz</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>L. -A. de Vaulchier</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.166601</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.166601" rel="related" />
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02159v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02159v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.other" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02160v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:17:53Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:17:53Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Human-in-the-Loop Policy Optimization for Preference-Based
  Multi-Objective Reinforcement Learning</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Multi-objective reinforcement learning (MORL) aims to find a set of
high-performing and diverse policies that address trade-offs between multiple
conflicting objectives. However, in practice, decision makers (DMs) often
deploy only one or a limited number of trade-off policies. Providing too many
diversified trade-off policies to the DM not only significantly increases their
workload but also introduces noise in multi-criterion decision-making. With
this in mind, we propose a human-in-the-loop policy optimization framework for
preference-based MORL that interactively identifies policies of interest. Our
method proactively learns the DM's implicit preference information without
requiring any a priori knowledge, which is often unavailable in real-world
black-box decision scenarios. The learned preference information is used to
progressively guide policy optimization towards policies of interest. We
evaluate our approach against three conventional MORL algorithms that do not
consider preference information and four state-of-the-art preference-based MORL
algorithms on two MORL environments for robot control and smart grid
management. Experimental results fully demonstrate the effectiveness of our
proposed method in comparison to the other peer algorithms.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ke Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Han Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>31 pages, 11 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02160v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02160v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02161v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:18:31Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:18:31Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Enhancing RAW-to-sRGB with Decoupled Style Structure in Fourier Domain</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  RAW to sRGB mapping, which aims to convert RAW images from smartphones into
RGB form equivalent to that of Digital Single-Lens Reflex (DSLR) cameras, has
become an important area of research. However, current methods often ignore the
difference between cell phone RAW images and DSLR camera RGB images, a
difference that goes beyond the color matrix and extends to spatial structure
due to resolution variations. Recent methods directly rebuild color mapping and
spatial structure via shared deep representation, limiting optimal performance.
Inspired by Image Signal Processing (ISP) pipeline, which distinguishes image
restoration and enhancement, we present a novel Neural ISP framework, named
FourierISP. This approach breaks the image down into style and structure within
the frequency domain, allowing for independent optimization. FourierISP is
comprised of three subnetworks: Phase Enhance Subnet for structural refinement,
Amplitude Refine Subnet for color learning, and Color Adaptation Subnet for
blending them in a smooth manner. This approach sharpens both color and
structure, and extensive evaluations across varied datasets confirm that our
approach realizes state-of-the-art results. Code will be available at
~\url{https://github.com/alexhe101/FourierISP}.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuanhua He</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tao Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Guoli Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zejin Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Run Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Qian Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Keyu Yan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ziyi Chen</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rui Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chenjun Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jie Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Man Zhou</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02161v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02161v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02162v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-10T01:59:28Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:19:54Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Frequency Domain Nuances Mining for Visible-Infrared Person
  Re-identification</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The key of visible-infrared person re-identification (VIReID) lies in how to
minimize the modality discrepancy between visible and infrared images. Existing
methods mainly exploit the spatial information while ignoring the
discriminative frequency information. To address this issue, this paper aims to
reduce the modality discrepancy from the frequency domain perspective.
Specifically, we propose a novel Frequency Domain Nuances Mining (FDNM) method
to explore the cross-modality frequency domain information, which mainly
includes an amplitude guided phase (AGP) module and an amplitude nuances mining
(ANM) module. These two modules are mutually beneficial to jointly explore
frequency domain visible-infrared nuances, thereby effectively reducing the
modality discrepancy in the frequency domain. Besides, we propose a
center-guided nuances mining loss to encourage the ANM module to preserve
discriminative identity information while discovering diverse cross-modality
nuances. Extensive experiments show that the proposed FDNM has significant
advantages in improving the performance of VIReID. Specifically, our method
outperforms the second-best method by 5.2\% in Rank-1 accuracy and 5.8\% in mAP
on the SYSU-MM01 dataset under the indoor search mode, respectively. Besides,
we also validate the effectiveness and generalization of our method on the
challenging visible-infrared face recognition task. \textcolor{magenta}{The
code will be available.}
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yukang Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yang Lu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yan Yan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hanzi Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuelong Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02162v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02162v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02163v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-05T11:18:05Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:20:36Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Enumerating m-Length Walks in Directed Graphs with Constant Delay</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this paper, we provide a novel enumeration algorithm for the set of all
walks of a given length within a directed graph. Our algorithm has worst-case
constant delay between outputting succinct representations of such walks, after
a preprocessing step requiring linear time relative to the size of the graph.
We apply these results to the problem of enumerating succinct representations
of the strings of a given length from a prefix-closed regular language
(languages accepted by a finite automaton which has final states only).
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Duncan Adamson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pawel Gawrychowski</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Florin Manea</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02163v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02163v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.DS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02164v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:22:14Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:22:14Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Listening broadband physical model for microphones: a first step</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We will present a first step in design of a broadband physical model for
microphones. Within the proposed model, classical directivity patterns
(omnidirectional, bidirectional and cardioids family) are refound as limit
cases: monochromatic excitation, low frequency and far-field approximation.
Monophonic pieces of music are used as sources for the model so we can listen
the simulation of the associated recorded sound field in realtime thanks to a
Max/MSP application. Listening and subbands analysis show that the directivity
is a function of frequential subband and source location. This model also
exhibits an interesting proximity effect. Audio demonstrations will be
given.Paper 6638 presented at the 120th Convention of the Audio Engineering
Society, Paris, 2006
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Laurent Millot</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Antoine Valette</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Manuel Lopes</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Gérard Pelé</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mohammed Elliq</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dominique Lambert</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>IDEAT</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:journal_ref>120th Convention of the Audio Engineering Society, Audio
  Engineering Society, May 2006, Paris, France</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02164v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02164v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="eess.AS" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02165v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-11-26T20:17:34Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:32:34Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Optimization of ionic configurations in battery materials by quantum
  annealing</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Energy materials with disorder in site occupation are challenging for
computational studies due to an exponential scaling of the configuration space.
We herein present a grand-canonical optimization method that enables the use of
quantum annealing (QA) for sampling the ionic ground state. The method relies
on a Legendre transformation of the Coulomb energy cost function that strongly
reduces the effective coupling strengths of the fully connected problem, which
is essential for effectiveness of QA. The approach is expected to be applicable
to a variety of materials optimization problems.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tobias Binninger</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yin-Ying Ting</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Piotr M. Kowalski</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael H. Eikerling</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.110.L180202</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.110.L180202" rel="related" />
    <ns2:journal_ref>Phys. Rev. B 110, L180202 (2024)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02165v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02165v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02166v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:33:44Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:33:44Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Temperature compensation in high accuracy accelerometers using
  multi-sensor and machine learning methods</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Temperature is a major source of inaccuracy in high-sensitivity
accelerometers and gravimeters. Active thermal control systems require power
and may not be ideal in some contexts such as airborne or spaceborne
applications. We propose a solution that relies on multiple thermometers placed
within the accelerometer to measure temperature and thermal gradient
variations. Machine Learning algorithms are used to relate the temperatures to
their effect on the accelerometer readings. However, obtaining labeled data for
training these algorithms can be difficult. Therefore, we also developed a
training platform capable of replicating temperature variations in a laboratory
setting. Our experiments revealed that thermal gradients had a significant
effect on accelerometer readings, emphasizing the importance of multiple
thermometers. The proposed method was experimentally tested and revealed a
great potential to be extended to other sources of inaccuracy, such as
rotations, as well as to other types of measuring systems, such as
magnetometers or gyroscopes.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lorenzo Iafolla</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Francesco Santoli</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Roberto Carluccio</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Stefano Chiappini</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Emiliano Fiorenza</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Carlo Lefevre</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pasqualino Loffredo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Marco Lucente</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alfredo Morbidini</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alessandro Pignatelli</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Massimo Chiappini</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1016/j.measurement.2023.114090</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.measurement.2023.114090" rel="related" />
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02166v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02166v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.ins-det" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.ins-det" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.geo-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02167v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:42:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:42:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Fake news: No ban, No spread -- with Sequestration</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Fake news is today a major threat to free and democratic making of public
opinion. To curb their spread, all efforts by institutions and policy makers
rely mainly on imposing restriction, prohibition and fact checking sites, which
end up to an effective limitation of freedom of speech. This policy of
prohibition, supported by a wide consensus, has been recently broken by the
controversial policy applied by Elon Musk to regulate the social media X, with
a backlash accusing him of promoting hate speech. Here, notwithstanding these
two policies, I explore another avenue denoted ``No ban, No spread - with
Sequestration", which amounts at the same time preserving full freedom of
speech and neutralization of fake news impact. To investigate the feasibility
of my proposal, I tackle the issue within the Galam model of opinion dynamics.
In addition to the basic ingredients of the model, I explore for the first time
the effect on the dynamics of opinion of a simultaneous activation of prejudice
tie breaking and contrarian behavior. The results show that indeed most pieces
of fake news do not propagate beyond small groups of people and thus pose no
global threat. However, I have unveiled some peculiar sets of parameters for
which fake news, even if initially shared by only a handful of agents, spreads
``naturally" to invade a whole community with no resistance. Based on these
findings, I am able to outline a path to neutralize such invasive fake news by
blocking "naturally" its spread, effectively sequestering it in very small
social networks of people. The scheme relies on reshaping the social geometry
of the landscape in which fake news evolves. No prohibition is required with
fake news left free to prosper but being sequestrated. Next challenging step
will be designing measures to implement the model's findings into the real
world of social media.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Serge Galam</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>31 pages, 9 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02167v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02167v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02168v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-25T12:00:42Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:48:32Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Supersymmetric Hybrid Inflation in Light of CMB Experiments and
  Swampland Conjectures</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  This study revisits supersymmetric (SUSY) hybrid inflation in light of CMB
experiments and swampland conjectures. We first show that if one adds
radiative, soft mass, and SUGRA corrections to the scalar potential,
supersymmetric hybrid inflation is still consistent with Planck 2018 despite an
impression that it does not. Usually, in SUSY hybrid inflation with minimal
K\"ahler potential, the gauge symmetry breaking scale $M$ turns out to be
${\cal O}(10^{15})$ GeV, which causes proton decay rate problem. In this study,
we present a new parameter space where the proton decay rate problem can be
avoided by achieving $M$ of the order of $10^{16}$ GeV with $M_{S}^{2}&lt;$0 and
$am_{3/2}&gt;$0. In this scenario, one requires a soft SUSY breaking scale
$|M_{S}| \gtrsim 10^{6}$ GeV. Moreover, the tensor to scalar ratio $r$ is in
the range $10^{-16}$ to $10^{-6}$, which is quite small. In this case, modified
swampland hold, but it is difficult to satisfy trans-Planckian censorship
conjecture. For this reason, we also consider non-minimal K\"ahler potential.
We fixed spectral index $n_{S}=$0.9665 (central value) of Planck 2018 data and
$M=2\times 10^{16}$ GeV and present our calculations. We show the canonical
measure of primordial gravity waves $r$ for $M_{S}=$ 1 TeV, $m_{3/2}=$ 1 TeV,
$\kappa_{S}&lt;0$ for $\cal{N}=$1 and $\cal{N}=$2, ranges from $10^{-5}$ to $0.01$
which can be observed in Planck and next-generation experiments such as
LiteBIRD, Simons Observatory, PRISM, PIXIE,CORE, CMB-S4 and CMB-HD experiments
that are gearing up to measure it. In addition to it, we present the parametric
space and benchmark points for a non-minimal case which is consistent with
modified swampland and trans-Planckian censorship conjectures.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Waqas Ahmed</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Shabbar Raza</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1088/1674-1137/ad7c27</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1674-1137/ad7c27" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>31 pages, 9 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02168v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02168v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02169v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:49:00Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:49:00Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Factors resisting protein adsorption on hydrophilic/hydrophobic
  self-assembled monolayers terminated with hydrophilic hydroxyl groups</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The hydroxyl-terminated self-assembled monolayer (OH-SAM), as a surface
resistant to protein adsorption, exhibits substantial potential in applications
such as ship navigation and medical implants, and the appropriate strategies
for designing anti-fouling surfaces are crucial. Here, we employ molecular
dynamics simulations and alchemical free energy calculations to systematically
analyze the factors influencing resistance to protein adsorption on the SAMs
terminated with single or double OH groups at three packing densities ({\Sigma}
= 2.0 nm-2, 4.5 nm-2, and 6.5 nm-2), respectively. For the first time, we
observe that the compactness and order of interfacial water enhance its
physical barrier effect, subsequently enhancing the resistance of SAM to
protein adsorption. Notably, the weak spatial hindrance effect of SAM leads to
the embedding of protein into SAM, resulting in a lack of resistance of SAM
towards protein. Furthermore, the number of hydroxyl groups per unit area of
double OH-terminated SAM at {\Sigma} = 6.5 nm-2 is approximately 2 to 3 times
that of single OH-terminated SAM at {\Sigma} = 6.5 nm-2 and 4.5 nm-2,
consequently yielding a weaker resistance of double OH-terminated SAM towards
protein. Meanwhile, due to the structure of SAM itself, i.e., the formation of
a nearly perfect ice-like hydrogen bond structure, the SAM exhibits the weakest
resistance towards protein. This study will complement and improve the
mechanism of OH-SAM resistance to protein adsorption, especially the
traditional barrier effect of interfacial water.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dangxin Mao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuan-Yan Wu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yusong Tu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02169v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02169v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="physics.bio-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.bio-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02170v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:49:12Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:49:12Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Non-conforming FEM for the quasi-static contact problem</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In this article, we addressed the numerical solution of a non-linear
evolutionary variational inequality, which is encountered in the investigation
of quasi-static contact problems. Our study encompasses both the semi-discrete
and fully-discrete schemes, where we employ the backward Euler method for time
discretization and utilize the lowest order Crouzeix-Raviart nonconforming
finite element method for spatial discretization. By assuming appropriate
regularity conditions on the solution, we establish \emph{a priori} error
analysis for these schemes, achieving the optimal convergence order for linear
elements. To illustrate the numerical convergence rates, we provide numerical
results on a two-dimensional test problem.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kamana Porwal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tanvi Wadhawan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02170v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02170v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02171v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:51:33Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:51:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Real-and-Present: Investigating the Use of Life-Size 2D Video Avatars in
  HMD-Based AR Teleconferencing</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Augmented Reality (AR) teleconferencing allows separately located users to
interact with each other in 3D through agents in their own physical
environments. Existing methods leveraging volumetric capturing and
reconstruction can provide a high-fidelity experience but are often too complex
and expensive for everyday usage. Other solutions target mobile and
effortless-to-setup teleconferencing on AR Head Mounted Displays (HMD). They
directly transplant the conventional video conferencing onto an AR-HMD platform
or use avatars to represent remote participants. However, they can only support
either a high fidelity or a high level of co-presence. Moreover, the limited
Field of View (FoV) of HMDs could further influence users' immersive
experience. To achieve a balance between fidelity and co-presence, we explore
using life-size 2D video-based avatars (video avatars for short) in AR
teleconferencing. Specifically, with the potential effect of FoV on users'
perception of proximity, we first conduct a pilot study to explore the
local-user-centered optimal placement of video avatars in small-group AR
conversations. With the placement results, we then implement a proof-of-concept
prototype of video-avatar-based teleconferencing. We conduct user evaluations
with the prototype to verify its effectiveness in balancing fidelity and
co-presence. Following the indication in the pilot study, we further
quantitatively explore the effect of FoV size on the video avatar's optimal
placement through a user study involving more FoV conditions in a VR-simulated
environment. We regress placement models to serve as references for
computationally determining video avatar placements in such teleconferencing
applications on various existing AR HMDs and future ones with bigger FoVs.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuanyu Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weizhan Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christian Sandor</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hongbo Fu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02171v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02171v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02172v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-06-04T05:13:28Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:52:00Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Recognition of Unit Segment and Polyline Graphs is
  $\exists\mathbb{R}$-Complete</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Given a set of objects O in the plane, the corresponding intersection graph
is defined as follows. A vertex is created for each object and an edge joins
two vertices whenever the corresponding objects intersect. We study here the
case of unit segments and polylines with exactly k bends. In the recognition
problem, we are given a graph and want to decide whether the graph can be
represented as the intersection graph of certain geometric objects. In previous
work it was shown that various recognition problems are
$\exists\mathbb{R}$-complete, leaving unit segments and polylines as few
remaining natural cases. We show that recognition for both families of objects
is $\exists\mathbb{R}$-complete.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michael Hoffmann</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tillmann Miltzow</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Simon Weber</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lasse Wulf</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>17 pages, 15 figures</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02172v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02172v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02173v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T09:55:15Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:55:15Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Prompt Decoupling for Text-to-Image Person Re-identification</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Text-to-image person re-identification (TIReID) aims to retrieve the target
person from an image gallery via a textual description query. Recently,
pre-trained vision-language models like CLIP have attracted significant
attention and have been widely utilized for this task due to their robust
capacity for semantic concept learning and rich multi-modal knowledge. However,
recent CLIP-based TIReID methods commonly rely on direct fine-tuning of the
entire network to adapt the CLIP model for the TIReID task. Although these
methods show competitive performance on this topic, they are suboptimal as they
necessitate simultaneous domain adaptation and task adaptation. To address this
issue, we attempt to decouple these two processes during the training stage.
Specifically, we introduce the prompt tuning strategy to enable domain
adaptation and propose a two-stage training approach to disentangle domain
adaptation from task adaptation. In the first stage, we freeze the two encoders
from CLIP and solely focus on optimizing the prompts to alleviate domain gap
between the original training data of CLIP and downstream tasks. In the second
stage, we maintain the fixed prompts and fine-tune the CLIP model to prioritize
capturing fine-grained information, which is more suitable for TIReID task.
Finally, we evaluate the effectiveness of our method on three widely used
datasets. Compared to the directly fine-tuned approach, our method achieves
significant improvements.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Weihao Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lei Tan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Pingyang Dai</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yan Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02173v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02173v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02174v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-05-18T09:24:52Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:56:07Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Detection and characterisation of icy cavities on the nucleus of comet
  67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We report on the detection of three icy cavities on the nucleus of comet
67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko. They were identified on high-resolution anaglyphs
built from images acquired by the OSIRIS instrument aboard the Rosetta
spacecraft on 2016 April 9-10. Visually, they appear as bright patches of
typically 15 to 30 m across whose large reflectances and spectral slopes in the
visible substantiate the presence of sub-surface water ice. Using a new
high-resolution photogrammetric shape model we determined the three-dimensional
shape of these cavities whose depth ranges from 20 to 47 m. Spectral slopes
were interpreted with models combining water ice and refractory dark material
and the water ice abundances in the cavities were found to amount to a few per
cent. The determination of the lifetime of the icy cavities was strongly biased
by the availability of appropriate and favourable observations, but we found
evidences of values of up to two years. The icy cavities were found to be
connected to jets well documented in past studies. A thermal model allowed us
to track their solar insolation over a large part of the orbit of the comet and
a transitory bright jet on 2015 July 18 was unambiguously linked to the brief
illumination of the icy bottom of one of the three cavities. These cavities are
likely to be the first potential subsurface access points detected on a
cometary nucleus and their lifetimes suggest that they reveal pristine
sub-surface icy layers or pockets rather than recently recondensed water vapor.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Philippe Lamy</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Laboratoire Atmospheres, Milieux et Observations Spatiales</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Guillaume Faury</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Institut de Recherche en Astrophysique et Planetologie</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>David Romeuf</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Universite Claude Bernard Lyon 1</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Olivier Groussin</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Aix Marseille Universite</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1093/mnras/stae1290</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1290" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>23 pages, 25 figures, 6 tables; one figure and references added.
  MNRAS in press</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02174v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02174v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02175v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-02-16T20:51:47Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T09:57:21Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>A simple quantum picture of the relativistic Doppler effect</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The relativistic Doppler effect comes from the fact that observers in
different inertial reference frames experience space and time differently,
while the speed of light remains always the same. Consequently, a wave packet
of light exhibits different frequencies, wavelengths, and amplitudes. In this
paper, we present a local approach to the relativistic Doppler effect based on
relativity, spatial and time translational symmetries, and energy conservation.
Afterwards we investigate the implications of the relativistic Doppler effect
for the quantum state transformations of wave packets of light and show that a
local photon is a local photon at the same point in the spacetime diagram in
all inertial frames.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Daniel Hodgson</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sara Kanzi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Almut Beige</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:comment>12 pages, 4 figures, more detailed discussions</ns2:comment>
    <ns2:journal_ref>Symmetry 16, 279 (2024)</ns2:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02175v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02175v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02176v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T10:02:08Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T10:02:08Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Pointwise A posteriori error control of quadratic Discontinuous Galerkin
  Methods for the unilateral contact problem</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  An a posteriori error bound for the pointwise error of the quadratic
discontinuous Galerkin method for the unilateral contact problem on polygonal
domain is presented. The pointwise a posteriori error analysis is based on the
direct use of a priori estimates of the Green's matrix for the divergence type
operators and the suitable construction of the discrete contact force density
$\b{\sigma}_h$ and barrier functions for the continuous solution. Several
numerical experiments (in two dimension) are presented to illustrate the
reliability and efficiency properties of the proposed aposteriori error
estimator.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rohit Khandelwal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kamana Porwal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tanvi Wadhawan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02176v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02176v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="math.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02177v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2024-01-04T10:02:57Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2024-01-04T10:02:57Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>NGC 2403 XMM4: evidence for a super-Eddington neutron star with a
  possible transient pulsation</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We present a study of the X-ray source NGC 2403 XMM4 (4XMM J073702.2+653934)
based on 20 years of archival observations with XMM-Newton, Chandra, Swift and
NuSTAR. Although it has previously been classified as an ultraluminous X-ray
source (ULX), we show that its luminosity rarely, if ever, passes the $10^{39}
\rm ~erg~s^{-1}$ threshold luminosity for a ULX. It does, however, behave very
similarly to ULXs, with its 0.3-10 keV spectra well described by two thermal
components, the softer of which behaves consistently with the expectations for
an advection-dominated disc ($L\propto T^{1.49\pm0.85}$), and we find tentative
evidence for an extra spectral component above 10 keV. We also find moderately
significant evidence for an absorption feature in one spectrum that could
originate in an outflowing wind, although a cyclotron resonance scattering
feature is also a possibility. Most intriguingly, we find a possible transient
pulsation at $\sim 3.32$ Hz in a short segment of one observation using an
accelerated pulsation search. This evidence suggests that NGC 2403 XMM4 is
displaying many of the hallmarks of super-Eddington accretion at luminosities
between $5 - 10 \times 10^{38} \rm ~erg~s^{-1}$ which, when considered
alongside the putative pulsation, points to the presence of a neutron star as
the accreting object this system.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>W. Luangtip</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Srinakharinwirot University</ns2:affiliation>
      <ns2:affiliation>National Astronomical Research Institute of Thailand</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>T. P. Roberts</ns0:name>
      <ns2:affiliation>Durham University</ns2:affiliation>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns2:doi>10.1093/mnras/stae023</ns2:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae023" rel="related" />
    <ns2:comment>15 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</ns2:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.02177v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.02177v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns2:primary_category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="astro-ph.HE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
</ns0:feed>